<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Automation on davidstamen</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/categories/automation/</link><description>Recent content in Automation on davidstamen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2008–2018, Steve Francia and the Hugo Authors; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 08:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidstamen.com/categories/automation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pure Cloud Block Store on AWS - Jump Start</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2021/07/26/pure-cloud-block-store-on-aws-jump-start/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2021/07/26/pure-cloud-block-store-on-aws-jump-start/</guid><description>&lt;p>In previous posts I have covered use cases on how to utilize Pure Cloud Block Store (CBS), but if we look back I haven&amp;rsquo;t explained how it can be deployed. This blog will cover how to easily get a &amp;ldquo;Jump Start&amp;rdquo; with the pre-requisites and get your Pure Cloud Block Store deployed in AWS.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pure Cloud Block Store on Azure - Jump Start</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2021/07/21/pure-cloud-block-store-on-azure-jump-start/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2021/07/21/pure-cloud-block-store-on-azure-jump-start/</guid><description>&lt;p>In previous posts I have covered use cases on how to utilize Pure Cloud Block Store (CBS), but if we look back I haven&amp;rsquo;t explained how it can be deployed. This blog will cover how to easily get a &amp;ldquo;Jump Start&amp;rdquo; with the pre-requisites and get your Pure Cloud Block Store deployed in Azure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Automating Deployment of vSphere Infrastructure on Equinix Metal</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2021/05/20/automating-deployment-of-vsphere-infrastructure-on-equinix-metal/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2021/05/20/automating-deployment-of-vsphere-infrastructure-on-equinix-metal/</guid><description>&lt;p>Did you know that Equinix has a Bare Metal as a Service (BMaaS) offering? Back in March Pure Storage also announced their Pure Storage® on Equinix Metal™ offering. This allows users to not only procure the Pure Storage FlashArray as an op-ex based purchase, but it also lets you spin up physical servers in Equinix Metal DC&amp;rsquo;s and connect them to a physical dedicated FlashArray. In this series I will cover how to deploy a vSphere environment on Equinix Metal with Terraform.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using an In-house Provider with Terraform v0.14</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2021/04/13/using-an-in-house-provider-with-terraform-v0.14/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2021/04/13/using-an-in-house-provider-with-terraform-v0.14/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ever wanted to update a Terraform Provider and not use the hosted Registry? Here at Pure Storage we have a Terraform Provider for Cloud Block Store and I wanted to do some testing myself. I started to pull my hair out trying to get Terraform to use my locally built provider instead of the registry. Check out this blog for a few simple steps to use a local in-house provider instead of the registry!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deploying a Linux EC2 Instance with Hashicorp Terraform and Vault to AWS and Connect to Pure Cloud Block Store</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-linux-ec2-using-terraform-vault/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-linux-ec2-using-terraform-vault/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another update to my &amp;ldquo;Terraforming AWS&amp;rdquo; series is the ability to deploy a Linux based Instance and connect to an existing data volume sitting on the Pure Cloud Block Store. This post will cover how to setup your environment and deploy and bootstrap your linux instance to connect via ISCSI.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deploying a EC2 Instance with PowerShell to AWS</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-ec2-using-powershell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-ec2-using-powershell/</guid><description>&lt;p>Previously, I covered how to Deploy and Bootstrap an EC2 Instance in AWS using Terraform. Not everyone may use Terraform, but quite a few people are using PowerShell today. Lets take a Look at how we can use AWSPowerShell to deploy an EC2 instance in AWS.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deploying a Windows Azure VM with Hashicorp Terraform to Microsoft Azure</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-avm-using-terraform/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-avm-using-terraform/</guid><description>&lt;p>As a followup to my previous post on Automating EC2 deployments, I figured why not show how this can also be done with Microsoft Azure? Check out how to launch an Azure VM instance and run some scripts to customize your installation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deploying a Windows EC2 Instance with Hashicorp Terraform and Vault to AWS</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-ec2-using-terraform-vault/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-ec2-using-terraform-vault/</guid><description>&lt;p>As part of demonstrating our products to customers, I tend to reprovision EC2 instances to show how easy it is to mount data in AWS to Cloud Block Store. After doing this manually a little too often, I figured why not automate it? Check out this blog on how I use Terraform to deploy a EC2 instance and configure it for in-guest iSCSI.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using Runecast to Check Pure Storage Best Practices</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/08/20/using-runecast-to-check-pure-storage-best-practices/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/08/20/using-runecast-to-check-pure-storage-best-practices/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today Runecast has announced the release of automated checks of VMware Best Practices for Pure Storage FlashArray! Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in and take a look!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using PowerCLI to Provision your Pure Storage Infrastructure</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/08/17/using-powercli-to-provision-your-pure-storage-infrastructure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/08/17/using-powercli-to-provision-your-pure-storage-infrastructure/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the continuation of my Automating your Pure Storage Infrastructure blog series, next I will be covering how to use PowerCLI to provision your Pure Storage Infrastructure. This has been one of the most popular ways to automate provisioning, and alot of work has been put into making this an ideal automation solution.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using Python to Provision your Pure Storage Infrastructure</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/08/13/using-python-to-provision-your-pure-storage-infrastructure/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/08/13/using-python-to-provision-your-pure-storage-infrastructure/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the continuation of my Automating your Pure Storage Infrastructure blog series, next I will be covering how to use Python to provision your Pure Storage Infrastructure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using Ansible to Provision your Pure Storage Infrastructure</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/08/12/using-ansible-to-provision-your-pure-storage-infrastructure/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/08/12/using-ansible-to-provision-your-pure-storage-infrastructure/</guid><description>&lt;p>I mentioned previously that there are many things I love about the Pure Storage Flasharray, but one of my favorite is how easy it is to integrate into different automation solutions. In this blog I will cover how to use Ansible to provision your Pure Storage Infrastructure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using Terraform to Provision your Pure Storage Infrastructure</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/08/06/using-terraform-to-provision-your-pure-storage-infrastructure/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/08/06/using-terraform-to-provision-your-pure-storage-infrastructure/</guid><description>&lt;p>There are many things I love about the Pure Storage Flasharray, but one of my favorite is how easy it is to integrate into different automation solutions. In this blog I will cover how to use Terraform to provision your Pure Storage Infrastructure. This will be the first post of many that show how easy it is to accomplish the same task using multiple automation methods.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>