<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Automation on davidstamen</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/categories/automation/</link><description>Recent content in Automation on davidstamen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2008–2018, Steve Francia and the Hugo Authors; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidstamen.com/categories/automation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deploying a EC2 Instance with PowerShell to AWS</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-ec2-using-powershell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-ec2-using-powershell/</guid><description>&lt;p>Previously, I covered how to Deploy and Bootstrap an EC2 Instance in AWS using Terraform. Not everyone may use Terraform, but quite a few people are using PowerShell today. Lets take a Look at how we can use AWSPowerShell to deploy an EC2 instance in AWS.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deploying a Windows Azure VM with Hashicorp Terraform to Microsoft Azure</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-avm-using-terraform/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-avm-using-terraform/</guid><description>&lt;p>As a followup to my previous post on Automating EC2 deployments, I figured why not show how this can also be done with Microsoft Azure? Check out how to launch an Azure VM instance and run some scripts to customize your installation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deploying a Windows EC2 Instance with Hashicorp Terraform and Vault to AWS</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-ec2-using-terraform-vault/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-ec2-using-terraform-vault/</guid><description>&lt;p>As part of demonstrating our products to customers, I tend to reprovision EC2 instances to show how easy it is to mount data in AWS to Cloud Block Store. After doing this manually a little too often, I figured why not automate it? Check out this blog on how I use Terraform to deploy a EC2 instance and configure it for in-guest iSCSI.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using Runecast to Check Pure Storage Best Practices</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/08/20/using-runecast-to-check-pure-storage-best-practices/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/08/20/using-runecast-to-check-pure-storage-best-practices/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today Runecast has announced the release of automated checks of VMware Best Practices for Pure Storage FlashArray! Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in and take a look!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using PowerCLI to Provision your Pure Storage Infrastructure</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/08/17/using-powercli-to-provision-your-pure-storage-infrastructure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/08/17/using-powercli-to-provision-your-pure-storage-infrastructure/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the continuation of my Automating your Pure Storage Infrastructure blog series, next I will be covering how to use PowerCLI to provision your Pure Storage Infrastructure. This has been one of the most popular ways to automate provisioning, and alot of work has been put into making this an ideal automation solution.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using Python to Provision your Pure Storage Infrastructure</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/08/13/using-python-to-provision-your-pure-storage-infrastructure/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/08/13/using-python-to-provision-your-pure-storage-infrastructure/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the continuation of my Automating your Pure Storage Infrastructure blog series, next I will be covering how to use Python to provision your Pure Storage Infrastructure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using Ansible to Provision your Pure Storage Infrastructure</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/08/12/using-ansible-to-provision-your-pure-storage-infrastructure/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/08/12/using-ansible-to-provision-your-pure-storage-infrastructure/</guid><description>&lt;p>I mentioned previously that there are many things I love about the Pure Storage Flasharray, but one of my favorite is how easy it is to integrate into different automation solutions. In this blog I will cover how to use Ansible to provision your Pure Storage Infrastructure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using Terraform to Provision your Pure Storage Infrastructure</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/08/06/using-terraform-to-provision-your-pure-storage-infrastructure/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/08/06/using-terraform-to-provision-your-pure-storage-infrastructure/</guid><description>&lt;p>There are many things I love about the Pure Storage Flasharray, but one of my favorite is how easy it is to integrate into different automation solutions. In this blog I will cover how to use Terraform to provision your Pure Storage Infrastructure. This will be the first post of many that show how easy it is to accomplish the same task using multiple automation methods.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>