<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VSphere Plugin on davidstamen</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/tags/vsphere-plugin/</link><description>Recent content in VSphere Plugin on davidstamen</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2008–2018, Steve Francia and the Hugo Authors; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidstamen.com/tags/vsphere-plugin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using Terraform to Deploy the Pure Storage VMware Appliance</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2021/07/30/using-terraform-to-deploy-the-pure-storage-vmware-appliance/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2021/07/30/using-terraform-to-deploy-the-pure-storage-vmware-appliance/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ive previously covered what&amp;rsquo;s new in the Pure Storage VMware Appliance and how to deploy it via PowerCLI, lets take a look at how to deploy the Pure Storage VMware Appliance using Terraform.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using PowerCLI to Deploy the Pure Storage VMware Appliance</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2021/07/29/using-powercli-to-deploy-the-pure-storage-vmware-appliance/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2021/07/29/using-powercli-to-deploy-the-pure-storage-vmware-appliance/</guid><description>&lt;p>Now that the latest Pure Storage vSphere Client Plugin is available as a remote plugin is is now deployed as an OVA. I have put together this quick script to automate deploying of the Pure Storage VMware Appliance.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What's New in the 5.0.0 Pure Storage Plugin for the vSphere Client</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2021/07/28/whats-new-in-the-5.0.0-pure-storage-plugin-for-the-vsphere-client/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2021/07/28/whats-new-in-the-5.0.0-pure-storage-plugin-for-the-vsphere-client/</guid><description>&lt;p>On July 28, 2021 Pure Storage released the latest version of their plugin version 5.0.0. Not only is this a new version, but it also runs on the new remote plugin architecture that VMware has released in vSphere 6.7U3 and vSphere 7.0+. This post will explore how to deploy and manage version 5.0.0 as well as discuss the latest features in this release! (Some are long awaited!)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What's New in the 4.3.1 Pure Storage vSphere Client Plugin</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/05/26/whats-new-in-the-4.3.1-pure-storage-vsphere-client-plugin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/05/26/whats-new-in-the-4.3.1-pure-storage-vsphere-client-plugin/</guid><description>&lt;p>In May 2020 Pure Storage released the latest version of their plugin version 4.3.1! This post will explore what&amp;rsquo;s new in this release!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What's New in the 4.3.0 Pure Storage vSphere Client Plugin</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/04/21/whats-new-in-the-4.3.0-pure-storage-vsphere-client-plugin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/04/21/whats-new-in-the-4.3.0-pure-storage-vsphere-client-plugin/</guid><description>&lt;p>On April 2, 2020 Pure Storage released the latest version of their plugin version 4.3.0! This post will explore the latest features in this release!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Configuring and Using the Pure Storage vSphere Plugin with Pure1 Authentication</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/03/25/configuring-and-using-the-pure-storage-vsphere-plugin-with-pure1-authentication/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/03/25/configuring-and-using-the-pure-storage-vsphere-plugin-with-pure1-authentication/</guid><description>&lt;p>Beginning with version 4.2.0 the Pure Storage vSphere Client Plugin had a whole slew of new features added, one of those features was the ability to integrate authentication with Pure1 allowing fleet registration of all your Pure Storage Arrays among other things. This does require a slight change on how you would normally register your arrays in the plugin, so lets take a look at how we can accomplish this!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using the Pure Storage vSphere Plugin</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/03/05/using-the-pure-storage-vsphere-plugin/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/03/05/using-the-pure-storage-vsphere-plugin/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome back! If you followed my previous post on Installing and Updating the Pure Storage vSphere Plugin, you may be wondering well What&amp;rsquo;s Next? Now its time to use it, which will empower your VMware Administrators to be awesome Pure Storage Administrators without ever needing to login to the Pure Storage UI!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Installing and Updating the Pure Storage vSphere Plugin</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/03/03/installing-and-updating-the-pure-storage-vsphere-plugin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/03/03/installing-and-updating-the-pure-storage-vsphere-plugin/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to the first of many Pure Storage blogs. As I get ramped up with the latest information I plan to do a series of getting started with Pure Storage features. These blogs will cover things such as the vSphere Client (HTML5) Plugin, FlashArray, FlashBlade and integrations with other VMware products. First up is learning to install and update the Pure Storage vSphere Client Plugin.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>