<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>FlashArray on davidstamen.com</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/tags/flasharray/</link><description>Recent content in FlashArray on davidstamen.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 08:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidstamen.com/tags/flasharray/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using the VMware Event Broker Appliance to Automatically Expand a Pure Storage FlashArray Datastore</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/using-veba-to-expand-pure-datastore/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/using-veba-to-expand-pure-datastore/</guid><description>&lt;p>Something we get asked quite often it seems here at Pure Storage, is can we automatically expand a datastore when it gets full? The answer is yes! With all of the integrations with automation platformsm, Pure Storage Arrays have many options. This blog will cover how to handle this with the VMware Event Broker Appliance (VEBA)!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Replacing the Pure Storage FlashArray VASA Certificate</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/04/01/replacing-the-pure-storage-flasharray-vasa-certificate/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/04/01/replacing-the-pure-storage-flasharray-vasa-certificate/</guid><description>&lt;p>Maintaining Certificates in your environments is an important thing to do to make connections between your client and server are encrypted. With this blog we will go over how to replace your Pure Storage FlashArray Certificate for the vStorage APIs for Storage Awareness (VASA) using a Microsoft Certificate Authority.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Replacing the Pure Storage FlashArray Management Certificate</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/03/31/replacing-the-pure-storage-flasharray-management-certificate/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/03/31/replacing-the-pure-storage-flasharray-management-certificate/</guid><description>&lt;p>Maintaining Certificates in your environments is an important thing to do to make connections between your client and server are encrypted. With this blog we will go over how to replace your Pure Storage FlashArray Management Certificate using a Microsoft Certificate Authority.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>