<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cisco on davidstamen.com</title>
    <link>http://davidstamen.com/tags/cisco/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cisco on davidstamen.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>davidstamen.com</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://davidstamen.com/tags/cisco/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting Cisco ENIC and FNIC Drivers with VMware Update Manager 6.x</title>
      <link>http://davidstamen.com/2016/04/08/troubleshooting-cisco-enic-and-fnic-drivers-with-vmware-update-manager-6x/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidstamen.com/2016/04/08/troubleshooting-cisco-enic-and-fnic-drivers-with-vmware-update-manager-6x/</guid>
      <description>I have been having issues ever since I updated to vSphere 6.x getting the Cisco Drivers to properly update through VMware Update Manager(VUM). Every time I would run through a compliance check, they would always report they were up to date even when they were running an older version.
I have recently made a breakthrough working with VMware Support and stumbling through some old blogs. Cisco Support has been terrible on this issue and after repeated attempts to get this case escalated i think the 10th time is a charm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using UCS PowerTool to Configure Syslog Servers</title>
      <link>http://davidstamen.com/2016/03/14/using-ucs-powertool-to-configure-syslog-servers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidstamen.com/2016/03/14/using-ucs-powertool-to-configure-syslog-servers/</guid>
      <description>Time for more UCS Scripting! This time to configure Syslog. The script is pretty straightforward, but nice to have to easily set up Syslog across multiple UCS domains.
Pre-Requsites  UCS Powertool  Link to Script  Set-UcsSyslog.ps1  Preparing to Execute the Script The script is pretty straight forward, just need to define a few variables seen below and then you execute the script. I will walk you through the process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using UCS PowerTool To Set SNMP Configuration</title>
      <link>http://davidstamen.com/2016/03/01/using-ucs-powertool-to-set-snmp-configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidstamen.com/2016/03/01/using-ucs-powertool-to-set-snmp-configuration/</guid>
      <description>Time for more UCS Scripting! This time to enable SNMP. The script is pretty straightforward, but nice to have to easily set up SNMP across multiple UCS domains.
Pre-Requsites  UCS Powertool  Link to Script  Set-UcsSnmpConfiguration.ps1  Preparing to Execute the Script The script is pretty straight forward, just need to define a few variables seen below and then you execute the script. I will walk you through the process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Ansible to Create Cisco ACI Filters</title>
      <link>http://davidstamen.com/2016/02/03/using-ansible-to-create-cisco-aci-filters/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidstamen.com/2016/02/03/using-ansible-to-create-cisco-aci-filters/</guid>
      <description>In the midst of rolling out Cisco ACI, we have a need to automation creation of filters to apply to contracts. I tried to use the ACI-PowerTool for this task, however it doesnt seem to work with the newer code we are on. So I went back and attempted to use the ansible modules and it worked flawlessly, below is a sample playbook that will create a filter and add the associated filter entries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco Champion 2016</title>
      <link>http://davidstamen.com/2016/01/31/cisco-champion-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidstamen.com/2016/01/31/cisco-champion-2016/</guid>
      <description>I am honored to have been accepted once again as a Cisco Champion for 2016!
I had a bit of a gap in blog posts this past year due to a job change. However, look forward to more posts on Cisco UCS and maybe even some Cisco ACI.
I am a member of the Cisco Champions Program. Cisco Champions are passionate about Cisco and enjoy sharing our knowledge, expertise, and thoughts across the social web and with Cisco.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using UCS PowerTool To Set Equipment Labels</title>
      <link>http://davidstamen.com/2016/01/15/using-ucs-powertool-to-set-equipment-labels/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidstamen.com/2016/01/15/using-ucs-powertool-to-set-equipment-labels/</guid>
      <description>For conformity, we like to set the UCS Equipment labels to match the Service Profile Name. This allows us to match it quickly without having to dig down into the assigned profile. This script will set the UsrLbl and Name fields on the equipment tab to match the name of the Service Profile.
Pre-Requsites  UCS Powertool  Link to Script  Set-UCSEquipmentLabel.ps1  Preparing to Execute the Script The script is pretty straight forward, just need to define a few variables seen below and then you execute the script.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using UCS PowerTool To Generate Tech Supports</title>
      <link>http://davidstamen.com/2016/01/14/using-ucs-powertool-to-generate-tech-supports/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidstamen.com/2016/01/14/using-ucs-powertool-to-generate-tech-supports/</guid>
      <description>Automation, Automation, Automation! I had to download some support bundles for every chassis in our multiple zones. Instead of manually going through the GUI, I figured why not script it! This script will connect to each UCS domain and automatically generate a support bundle and download it for each chassis.
Pre-Requsites  UCS Powertool  Link to Script  Create-UCSTechSupport.ps1  Preparing to Execute the Script The script is pretty straight forward, just need to define a few variables seen below and then you execute the script.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using UCS PowerTool To Upload UCS Firmware</title>
      <link>http://davidstamen.com/2016/01/11/using-ucs-powertool-to-upload-ucs-firmware/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidstamen.com/2016/01/11/using-ucs-powertool-to-upload-ucs-firmware/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s patch time! That means time to upload the firmware bundles to all my UCS domains. Instead of doing it manually I figured i would create a quick script to do that for me.
Pre-Requsites  UCS Powertool  Link to Script  UploadUCSFirmware.ps1  Preparing to Execute the Script The script is pretty straight forward, just need to define a few variables seen below and then you execute the script.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using UCS PowerTool To Configure UCS Policy Backup and Export</title>
      <link>http://davidstamen.com/2015/12/11/using-ucs-powertool-to-configure-ucs-policy-backup-and-export/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidstamen.com/2015/12/11/using-ucs-powertool-to-configure-ucs-policy-backup-and-export/</guid>
      <description>Im finally getting to dive back in to working with UCS. My latest task with my project of configuring 9 UCS Domains, was configuring the Policy Backup and Export. See below on how to automate this process!
Pre-Requsites  UCS Powertool  Link to Script  Set-UCSPolicyBackupandExport.ps1  Preparing to Execute the Script The script is pretty straight forward, just need to define a few variables seen below and then you execute the script.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using UCS PowerTool To Configure UCS Certificates</title>
      <link>http://davidstamen.com/2015/12/10/using-ucs-powertool-to-configure-ucs-certificates/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidstamen.com/2015/12/10/using-ucs-powertool-to-configure-ucs-certificates/</guid>
      <description>Im finally getting to dive back in to working with UCS. My latest task with my project of configuring 9 UCS Domains, was swapping out certificates. The first few I did via the GUI, and I thought can this be scripted? Well the answer is yes! See below for information on executing the script.
Pre-Requsites  UCS Powertool  Link to Script  AddUCSCert.ps1  Preparing to Execute the Script The script is pretty straight forward, just need to define a few variables seen below and then you execute the script.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Multiple UCS VLAN&#39;s</title>
      <link>http://davidstamen.com/2015/11/23/configuring-multiple-ucs-vlans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidstamen.com/2015/11/23/configuring-multiple-ucs-vlans/</guid>
      <description>We are currently working on some Cisco ACI Integration and wanted to add a large VLAN Pool to a UCS Configuration.
Since currently Cisco UCS does not allow selecting multiple VLAN&amp;rsquo;s easily when adding to a VLAN Group or vNIC Template, we now have a pretty decent script that will do it for you.
The script can be found here.
# PowerCLI Script for adding VLAN to VLAN Group and vNIC Template # @davidstamen # http://davidstamen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco Champion 2015</title>
      <link>http://davidstamen.com/2014/11/26/cisco-champion-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidstamen.com/2014/11/26/cisco-champion-2015/</guid>
      <description>I am honored to have been accepted as a Cisco Champion for 2015! I guess this means I will continue and post to expand content on Cisco UCS and Cisco IronPort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco UCS and Native VLAN Tagging</title>
      <link>http://davidstamen.com/2014/04/29/cisco-ucs-and-native-vlan-tagging/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidstamen.com/2014/04/29/cisco-ucs-and-native-vlan-tagging/</guid>
      <description>Building out some new servers today I came across an issue where the servers would have no network connectivity even though the vNICs were properly tagged and assign a VLAN ID. Upon further research, I noticed that &amp;ldquo;Native VLAN&amp;rdquo; was not selected. This is a must for any operating system that does not do VLAN Tagging such as ESXi.
So remember to set the VLAN to Native if using an operating system that does not support VLAN tagging!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>