<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>vSphere on davidstamen.com</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/tags/vsphere/</link><description>Recent content in vSphere on davidstamen.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 08:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidstamen.com/tags/vsphere/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using the VMware Event Broker Appliance to Automatically Expand a Pure Storage FlashArray Datastore</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/using-veba-to-expand-pure-datastore/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/using-veba-to-expand-pure-datastore/</guid><description>&lt;p>Something we get asked quite often it seems here at Pure Storage, is can we automatically expand a datastore when it gets full? The answer is yes! With all of the integrations with automation platformsm, Pure Storage Arrays have many options. This blog will cover how to handle this with the VMware Event Broker Appliance (VEBA)!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Updating the vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) with PowerCLI - Revisited</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/06/22/updating-the-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-with-powercli-revisited/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/06/22/updating-the-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-with-powercli-revisited/</guid><description>In previous blogs, I covered how to update your VCSA using PowerCLI and with Postman. I also had multiple code sessions at VMworld 2019 where I got great feedback on the module. It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I have looked at the module, and time has passed so I thought it was due for an update. The module will no longer need to be manually imported, it is now located in the Powershell Gallery!</description></item><item><title>Configuring vRealize Orchestrator to use Pure1 Integration</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/06/05/configuring-vrealize-orchestrator-to-use-pure1-integration/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/06/05/configuring-vrealize-orchestrator-to-use-pure1-integration/</guid><description>&lt;p>The more I play with our integrations the more I am impressed. My latest project within vRealize Orchestrator had me utilizing our Pure1 integration. This post will cover how to generate the needed pieces to configure the Pure1 Integration within vRO.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Unable to Provision a vVol Hard Disk on a VM Located on VMFS Datastore</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/06/02/unable-to-provision-a-vvol-hard-disk-on-a-vm-located-on-vmfs-datastore/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/06/02/unable-to-provision-a-vvol-hard-disk-on-a-vm-located-on-vmfs-datastore/</guid><description>&lt;p>An interesting issue came in from one of our customers that they were unable to provision a new vVol Disk on a VM that was based on a VMFS Datastore. After some troubleshooting it seems there was a regression which no longer makes this available in the UI. Take a look at this blog post on how I will cover a workaround.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Updating a vSphere with Kubernetes Supervisor Cluster</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/updating-vk8s-supervisor-cluster/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/updating-vk8s-supervisor-cluster/</guid><description>&lt;p>With the release of the first vSphere 7.0 update we now are seeing how updates for vSphere with Kubernetes environments can be completed! Let&amp;rsquo;s dive into this post to see how I completed the upgrade of my vSphere with Kubernetes environment.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deploying Tanzu Kubernetes Clusters (TKC) on vSphere with Kubernetes using the TKG CLI</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/deploying-tkc-on-vk8s-using-tkgcli/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/deploying-tkc-on-vk8s-using-tkgcli/</guid><description>&lt;p>Tanzu Kubernetes Grid (TKG) is a great tool to deploy VMware Kubernetes on different Platforms. In previous blogs I covered how you could deploy a TKG to VMware Cloud on AWS as well as to a regular vSphere Environment. Today we will demonstrate how to use the TKG CLI to provision a Tanzu Kubernetes Cluster (TKC) to a vSphere With Kubernetes Environment.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deploying Tanzu Kubernetes Grid (TKG) on vSphere</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/deploying-tkg-on-vsphere/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/deploying-tkg-on-vsphere/</guid><description>&lt;p>Tanzu Kubernetes Grid (TKG) is part of VMware&amp;rsquo;s new Tanzu Portfolio of products. I have done quite a bit with vSphere with Kubernetes and Tanzu Kubernetes Clusters on vSphere with Kubernetes, but something came up and I began to explore native TKG. This blog will cover how to deploy TKG on vSphere and get your management and tkc clusters provisioned.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Considerations for vSphere Component Backup and Restore: Part 2</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2019/10/23/considerations-for-vsphere-component-backup-and-restore-part-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2019/10/23/considerations-for-vsphere-component-backup-and-restore-part-2/</guid><description>Now that we have covered the considerations to backup each component in your vSphere Environment, it&amp;rsquo;s time to think about the rollback or restore process. In the previous post we discussed how to backup each individual component, in this post we will continue the conversation and discuss considerations to restore or rollback your vSphere Environment components.
Platform Services Controller / vCenter Server When things don&amp;rsquo;t go right with an update, upgrade or configuration change of your Platform Services Controller or vCenter Server you need to understand the proper steps it takes to rollback.</description></item><item><title>Considerations for vSphere Component Backup and Restore: Part 1</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2019/10/21/considerations-for-vsphere-component-backup-and-restore-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2019/10/21/considerations-for-vsphere-component-backup-and-restore-part-1/</guid><description>You spend time planning and implementing updates, upgrades and configuration changes to vSphere Environments. Rollback or recovery is usually the last thing on the mind. Did you know there are multiple ways to successfully backup each component in a vSphere Environment? There are also many ways to recover those same components.
In this series we will talk about considerations to backup and restore or rollback your vSphere environment if we have a need to.</description></item><item><title>Patching the vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) using the REST API - Part 2 (PowerCLI Module)</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2019/01/31/patching-the-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-using-the-rest-api-part-2-powershell-module/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2019/01/31/patching-the-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-using-the-rest-api-part-2-powershell-module/</guid><description>Previously I covered how to use the VCSA Installer to do a scripted upgrade and then I covered Patching the vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) using the REST API - Part 1 (Postman Collection) However, after learning recently how to call API&amp;rsquo;s from Powershell I thought to myself, why not write a Powershell Module for this?
Introduction Using tools such as Postman can make it utilizing API&amp;rsquo;s a bit easier, but you still need to be familiar with a separate tool or UI.</description></item></channel></rss>