<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VSphere on davidstamen</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/tags/vsphere/</link><description>Recent content in VSphere on davidstamen</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2008–2018, Steve Francia and the Hugo Authors; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidstamen.com/tags/vsphere/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What's New in Pure1 VM Analytics and OVA Collector 3.0</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/whats-new-vm-analytics-collector-3-0/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/whats-new-vm-analytics-collector-3-0/</guid><description>&lt;p>On November 16, 2020 the latest version of the Pure1 VM Analytics OVA Collector (3.0) was released and with it comes some new Pure1 features! Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at how the collector has changed, and what new features we now have within Pure1 VM Analytics.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using Pure1 Meta for Intelligent Datastore Selection and VM Provisioning</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/11/11/using-pure1-meta-for-intelligent-datastore-selection-and-vm-provisioning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/11/11/using-pure1-meta-for-intelligent-datastore-selection-and-vm-provisioning/</guid><description>&lt;p>When it comes to monitoring your Pure Storage environment Pure1 is a great place for that. It is also a great place to use your analytic&amp;rsquo;s data to your advantage and use it for intelligent VMware provisioning! In this blog post I will cover how to use this data to your advantage to make sure you can easily deploy VM&amp;rsquo;s to the most optimal array and datastore.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using the VMware Event Broker Appliance to Automatically Expand a Pure Storage FlashArray Datastore</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/using-veba-to-expand-pure-datastore/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/using-veba-to-expand-pure-datastore/</guid><description>&lt;p>Something we get asked quite often it seems here at Pure Storage, is can we automatically expand a datastore when it gets full? The answer is yes! With all of the integrations with automation platformsm, Pure Storage Arrays have many options. This blog will cover how to handle this with the VMware Event Broker Appliance (VEBA)!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Unable to Provision a vVol Hard Disk on a VM Located on VMFS Datastore</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/06/02/unable-to-provision-a-vvol-hard-disk-on-a-vm-located-on-vmfs-datastore/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/06/02/unable-to-provision-a-vvol-hard-disk-on-a-vm-located-on-vmfs-datastore/</guid><description>&lt;p>An interesting issue came in from one of our customers that they were unable to provision a new vVol Disk on a VM that was based on a VMFS Datastore. After some troubleshooting it seems there was a regression which no longer makes this available in the UI. Take a look at this blog post on how I will cover a workaround.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Considerations for vSphere Component Backup and Restore: Part 2</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2019/10/23/considerations-for-vsphere-component-backup-and-restore-part-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2019/10/23/considerations-for-vsphere-component-backup-and-restore-part-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Now that we have covered the considerations to backup each component in your vSphere Environment, it&amp;rsquo;s time to think about the rollback or restore process. In the previous post we discussed how to backup each individual component, in this post we will continue the conversation and discuss considerations to restore or rollback your vSphere Environment components.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="platform-services-controller--vcenter-server">Platform Services Controller / vCenter Server&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When things don&amp;rsquo;t go right with an update, upgrade or configuration change of your Platform Services Controller or vCenter Server you need to understand the proper steps it takes to rollback. In these scenarios sometimes there may have been a failure in the process, or after a successful upgrade was completed, an incompatibility was found which would result in a rollback. A reason we see the need to rollback a vCenter Server is when a supporting solution such as a backup vendor or monitoring vendor is not compatible. In this case you will need to revert to the previous version.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Considerations for vSphere Component Backup and Restore: Part 1</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2019/10/21/considerations-for-vsphere-component-backup-and-restore-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2019/10/21/considerations-for-vsphere-component-backup-and-restore-part-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>You spend time planning and implementing updates, upgrades and configuration changes to vSphere Environments. Rollback or recovery is usually the last thing on the mind. Did you know there are multiple ways to successfully backup each component in a vSphere Environment? There are also many ways to recover those same components.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this series we will talk about considerations to backup and restore or rollback your vSphere environment if we have a need to.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Patching the vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) using the REST API - Part 2 (PowerCLI Module)</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2019/01/31/patching-the-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-using-the-rest-api-part-2-powershell-module/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2019/01/31/patching-the-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-using-the-rest-api-part-2-powershell-module/</guid><description>&lt;p>Previously I covered how to use the &lt;a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/vsphere/2018/09/upgrading-platform-services-controller-and-vcenter-server-via-the-cli-installer.html?cid=70134000001kxaB&amp;amp;src=so_5c783ca7348a0">VCSA Installer to do a scripted upgrade&lt;/a> and then I covered &lt;a href="https://davidstamen.com/2018/12/20/patching-the-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-using-the-rest-api/">Patching the vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) using the REST API - Part 1 (Postman Collection)&lt;/a> However, after learning recently how to call API&amp;rsquo;s from Powershell I thought to myself, why not write a Powershell Module for this?&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Using tools such as &lt;a href="https://www.getpostman.com/">Postman&lt;/a> can make it utilizing API&amp;rsquo;s a bit easier, but you still need to be familiar with a separate tool or UI. I was able to develop my own version and build my first Powershell Module that you can use to patch the VCSA in a simple method. Some of the function names below may not be 100% exact and this is due to the accepted verbs for Powershell. If you have further recommendations I would be happy to entertain changing the Powershell verbage.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>