<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vcenter on davidstamen.com</title>
    <link>http://davidstamen.com/tags/vcenter/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vcenter on davidstamen.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 16:08:43 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://davidstamen.com/tags/vcenter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>vCenter 6.5U1 Update Issues with VCHA Advanced Deployment</title>
      <link>http://davidstamen.com/2017/08/vCenter-6.5U1-Update-Issues-with-VCHA-Advanced-Deployment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 16:08:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidstamen.com/2017/08/vCenter-6.5U1-Update-Issues-with-VCHA-Advanced-Deployment/</guid>
      <description>vSphere 6.5U1 was released on July 27th. This is an incremental update a lot of people wait for before upgrading from a previous version. I have been lucky to have been running on vSphere 6.5 for quite some time and have been enjoying it very much.
Obviously we never upgrade production first, if we can help it. I decided to attempt an upgrade on one of our QA vCenters that was deployed using the VCHA Advanced workflow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using PowerCLI to Set vCenter Permissions on Datacenter</title>
      <link>http://davidstamen.com/2017/04/17/using-powercli-to-set-vcenter-permissions-on-datacenter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidstamen.com/2017/04/17/using-powercli-to-set-vcenter-permissions-on-datacenter/</guid>
      <description>I have been working on doing a vCenter Consolidation Project. This has meant recreating multiple permissions groups. I couldnt find an easy way to apply permissions at a datacenter so I updated this script to be used.
Pre-Requsites  VMware PowerCLI  Link to Script  Set-vCenterPermissions.ps1 permissions.csv  Preparing to Execute the Script The script is pretty straight forward, just need to update columns in the CSV such as Datacenter, Group and Role.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vSphere 6.5 - Updating Appliance configured with vCenter HA</title>
      <link>http://davidstamen.com/2017/02/03/vsphere-65-updating-appliance-configured-with-vcenter-ha/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidstamen.com/2017/02/03/vsphere-65-updating-appliance-configured-with-vcenter-ha/</guid>
      <description>Warning: A few others and myself have noticed that when updating a VCHA Cluster to 6.5U1 it resets the hostname to localhost.localdomain stopping vCenter Web Client from Loading. It seems to be isolated to Advanced Deployments and not Basic. I would recommend destroying your VCHA Cluster, updating, then redeploying in this scenario. Warning2: It also seems that if you try to redeploy VCHA Advanced after an upgrade, it still resets the hostname, I have a case opened and will update here as neccessary.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>