<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VM Analytics on davidstamen</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/tags/vm-analytics/</link><description>Recent content in VM Analytics on davidstamen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2008–2018, Steve Francia and the Hugo Authors; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidstamen.com/tags/vm-analytics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using Terraform to Deploy the Pure Storage VMware Appliance</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2021/07/30/using-terraform-to-deploy-the-pure-storage-vmware-appliance/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2021/07/30/using-terraform-to-deploy-the-pure-storage-vmware-appliance/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ive previously covered what&amp;rsquo;s new in the Pure Storage VMware Appliance and how to deploy it via PowerCLI, lets take a look at how to deploy the Pure Storage VMware Appliance using Terraform.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using PowerCLI to Deploy the Pure Storage VMware Appliance</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2021/07/29/using-powercli-to-deploy-the-pure-storage-vmware-appliance/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2021/07/29/using-powercli-to-deploy-the-pure-storage-vmware-appliance/</guid><description>&lt;p>Now that the latest Pure Storage vSphere Client Plugin is available as a remote plugin is is now deployed as an OVA. I have put together this quick script to automate deploying of the Pure Storage VMware Appliance.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What's New in Pure1 VM Analytics and OVA Collector 3.1.0</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2021/04/19/whats-new-in-pure1-vm-analytics-and-ova-collector-3.1.0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2021/04/19/whats-new-in-pure1-vm-analytics-and-ova-collector-3.1.0/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Pure Storage OVA is a single OVA deployment that can be configured for different roles. Today VM Analytics is the only available role, with more coming. Version 3.1.0 includes some new features and fixes, lets dive in and take a look.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What's New in Pure1 VM Analytics and OVA Collector 3.0</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/whats-new-vm-analytics-collector-3-0/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/whats-new-vm-analytics-collector-3-0/</guid><description>&lt;p>On November 16, 2020 the latest version of the Pure1 VM Analytics OVA Collector (3.0) was released and with it comes some new Pure1 features! Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at how the collector has changed, and what new features we now have within Pure1 VM Analytics.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using Terraform to Deploy the Pure1 VM Analytics Collector</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/06/30/using-terraform-to-deploy-the-pure1-vm-analytics-collector/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 07:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/06/30/using-terraform-to-deploy-the-pure1-vm-analytics-collector/</guid><description>&lt;p>Pure1 VM Analytics is a great tool to have in your environment. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to even have a Pure Storage array, but it makes it even better! Back in 2019 the collector was converted to an OVA format and has been much simpler to deploy. You can deploy it through the UI or even Powershell. With the latest update to the Terraform vSphere provider we can now deploy OVA&amp;rsquo;s, so lets jump in to see how we can deploy the VM Analytics collector!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>