<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pure Storage on davidstamen.com</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/categories/pure-storage/</link><description>Recent content in Pure Storage on davidstamen.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 08:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidstamen.com/categories/pure-storage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Running vVols in VMware Cloud on AWS (VMC) on Pure Storage Cloud Block Store (CBS) on AWS</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/running-vvol-on-vmc-on-cbs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/running-vvol-on-vmc-on-cbs/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another post of a cool project this week. With the tools we have available during our hackathon it was asked if we could run vVols in VMware Cloud on AWS. Because of the locked down nature of VMC we could not run vVols directly on that cluster, but I did find a way that we could. Dive into this blog post to see how vVols run on CBS.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What's New in the Pure Storage vRealize Operations Management Pack 3.0</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/04/24/whats-new-in-the-pure-storage-vrealize-operations-management-pack-3.0/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/04/24/whats-new-in-the-pure-storage-vrealize-operations-management-pack-3.0/</guid><description>&lt;p>Released on April 15, 2020 the long awaited Pure Storage vRealize Operations Management Pack 3.0 is here!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What's New in the 4.3.0 Pure Storage vSphere Client Plugin</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/04/21/whats-new-in-the-4.3.0-pure-storage-vsphere-client-plugin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/04/21/whats-new-in-the-4.3.0-pure-storage-vsphere-client-plugin/</guid><description>&lt;p>On April 2, 2020 Pure Storage released the latest version of their plugin version 4.3.0! This post will explore the latest features in this release!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Replacing the Pure Storage FlashArray VASA Certificate</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/04/01/replacing-the-pure-storage-flasharray-vasa-certificate/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/04/01/replacing-the-pure-storage-flasharray-vasa-certificate/</guid><description>&lt;p>Maintaining Certificates in your environments is an important thing to do to make connections between your client and server are encrypted. With this blog we will go over how to replace your Pure Storage FlashArray Certificate for the vStorage APIs for Storage Awareness (VASA) using a Microsoft Certificate Authority.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Replacing the Pure Storage FlashArray Management Certificate</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/03/31/replacing-the-pure-storage-flasharray-management-certificate/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/03/31/replacing-the-pure-storage-flasharray-management-certificate/</guid><description>&lt;p>Maintaining Certificates in your environments is an important thing to do to make connections between your client and server are encrypted. With this blog we will go over how to replace your Pure Storage FlashArray Management Certificate using a Microsoft Certificate Authority.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Configuring and Using the Pure Storage vSphere Plugin with Pure1 Authentication</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/03/25/configuring-and-using-the-pure-storage-vsphere-plugin-with-pure1-authentication/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/03/25/configuring-and-using-the-pure-storage-vsphere-plugin-with-pure1-authentication/</guid><description>&lt;p>Beginning with version 4.2.0 the Pure Storage vSphere Client Plugin had a whole slew of new features added, one of those features was the ability to integrate authentication with Pure1 allowing fleet registration of all your Pure Storage Arrays among other things. This does require a slight change on how you would normally register your arrays in the plugin, so lets take a look at how we can accomplish this!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using vRealize Automation with the Pure Storage vRealize Orchestrator Plugin</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/03/20/using-vrealize-automation-with-the-pure-storage-vrealize-orchestrator-plugin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/03/20/using-vrealize-automation-with-the-pure-storage-vrealize-orchestrator-plugin/</guid><description>&lt;p>Moving forward with Automation, we will now expand our horizons past vRealize Orchestrator (vRO) into vRealize Automation (vRA)! Our integration with vRA utilizes the vRO Plugin and allows users to self-provision their infrastructure using all the goodness included with vRA such as blueprints, approval workflows and reservations. Lets Dive in and take a look!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using the Pure Storage vRealize Orchestrator Plugin</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/03/16/using-the-pure-storage-vrealize-orchestrator-plugin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/03/16/using-the-pure-storage-vrealize-orchestrator-plugin/</guid><description>&lt;p>Adding to the series of VMware and Pure Storage blogs is Automation! When it comes to automating your VMware Environment with Pure Storage we have a vRO Plugin for you! Dive in and take a look at how you can get your environment automated.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using the Pure Storage vRealize Operations Management Pack</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/03/10/using-the-pure-storage-vrealize-operations-management-pack/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/03/10/using-the-pure-storage-vrealize-operations-management-pack/</guid><description>&lt;p>When it comes to monitoring your Pure Storage environment, Pure1 is an amazing tool. However, some customers have an investment in the VMware vRealize Suite and wish to look at some of the Pure Storage Array information within their vRealize Operations environment.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using the Pure Storage vSphere Plugin</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/03/05/using-the-pure-storage-vsphere-plugin/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/03/05/using-the-pure-storage-vsphere-plugin/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome back! If you followed my previous post on Installing and Updating the Pure Storage vSphere Plugin, you may be wondering well What&amp;rsquo;s Next? Now its time to use it, which will empower your VMware Administrators to be awesome Pure Storage Administrators without ever needing to login to the Pure Storage UI!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Installing and Updating the Pure Storage vSphere Plugin</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/03/03/installing-and-updating-the-pure-storage-vsphere-plugin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/03/03/installing-and-updating-the-pure-storage-vsphere-plugin/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to the first of many Pure Storage blogs. As I get ramped up with the latest information I plan to do a series of getting started with Pure Storage features. These blogs will cover things such as the vSphere Client (HTML5) Plugin, FlashArray, FlashBlade and integrations with other VMware products. First up is learning to install and update the Pure Storage vSphere Client Plugin.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Back to Work, I'm Going to</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/02/12/back-to-work-im-going-to/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/02/12/back-to-work-im-going-to/</guid><description>When the unfortunate reduction in force (RIF) struck in January at VMware, I was in disbelief and didn&amp;rsquo;t even know where to start. Over the past two years I had the amazing opportunity to not only present to customers and partners in places I never imagined, but the ability to be an internal subject matter expert and create some amazing content. VMware is an amazing place to work and the relationships I&amp;rsquo;ve made and my impact to the products are beyond things I thought I could ever accomplish.</description></item></channel></rss>