<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pure Storage on davidstamen</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/categories/pure-storage/</link><description>Recent content in Pure Storage on davidstamen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2008–2018, Steve Francia and the Hugo Authors; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 08:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidstamen.com/categories/pure-storage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using the Pure Storage Cloud Block Store Terraform Provider for AWS</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2021/02/10/using-the-pure-storage-cloud-block-store-terraform-provider-for-aws/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2021/02/10/using-the-pure-storage-cloud-block-store-terraform-provider-for-aws/</guid><description>&lt;p>Im excited to announce the first release of the Pure Storage Cloud Block Store (CBS) Terraform Provider. The first release introduces support for Cloud Block Store on AWS. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in and take a look at how to utilize the new provider!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What's New in Pure1 VM Analytics and OVA Collector 3.0</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/whats-new-vm-analytics-collector-3-0/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/whats-new-vm-analytics-collector-3-0/</guid><description>&lt;p>On November 16, 2020 the latest version of the Pure1 VM Analytics OVA Collector (3.0) was released and with it comes some new Pure1 features! Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at how the collector has changed, and what new features we now have within Pure1 VM Analytics.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Backup and Restore Kubernetes Applications Using Portworx</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/backup-restore-k8s-with-portworx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/backup-restore-k8s-with-portworx/</guid><description>&lt;p>When deploying any enterprise application it is always important to think about the BC/DR strategy. Containers work really great from a Business Continuity perspective as they are stateless, but what happens if you lose the entire datacenter? What happens if you need to migrate an application to another site? PX-Backup from Portworx by Pure Storage is a great tool for this! Lets take a look how we can backup and restore applications using PX-Backup&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deploying a Linux EC2 Instance with Hashicorp Terraform and Vault to AWS and Connect to Pure Cloud Block Store</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-linux-ec2-using-terraform-vault/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-linux-ec2-using-terraform-vault/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another update to my &amp;ldquo;Terraforming AWS&amp;rdquo; series is the ability to deploy a Linux based Instance and connect to an existing data volume sitting on the Pure Cloud Block Store. This post will cover how to setup your environment and deploy and bootstrap your linux instance to connect via ISCSI.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using Pure1 Meta for Intelligent Datastore Selection and VM Provisioning</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/11/11/using-pure1-meta-for-intelligent-datastore-selection-and-vm-provisioning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/11/11/using-pure1-meta-for-intelligent-datastore-selection-and-vm-provisioning/</guid><description>&lt;p>When it comes to monitoring your Pure Storage environment Pure1 is a great place for that. It is also a great place to use your analytic&amp;rsquo;s data to your advantage and use it for intelligent VMware provisioning! In this blog post I will cover how to use this data to your advantage to make sure you can easily deploy VM&amp;rsquo;s to the most optimal array and datastore.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using Runecast to Check Pure Storage Best Practices</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/08/20/using-runecast-to-check-pure-storage-best-practices/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/08/20/using-runecast-to-check-pure-storage-best-practices/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today Runecast has announced the release of automated checks of VMware Best Practices for Pure Storage FlashArray! Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in and take a look!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using PowerCLI to Provision your Pure Storage Infrastructure</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/08/17/using-powercli-to-provision-your-pure-storage-infrastructure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/08/17/using-powercli-to-provision-your-pure-storage-infrastructure/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the continuation of my Automating your Pure Storage Infrastructure blog series, next I will be covering how to use PowerCLI to provision your Pure Storage Infrastructure. This has been one of the most popular ways to automate provisioning, and alot of work has been put into making this an ideal automation solution.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using Python to Provision your Pure Storage Infrastructure</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/08/13/using-python-to-provision-your-pure-storage-infrastructure/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/08/13/using-python-to-provision-your-pure-storage-infrastructure/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the continuation of my Automating your Pure Storage Infrastructure blog series, next I will be covering how to use Python to provision your Pure Storage Infrastructure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using Ansible to Provision your Pure Storage Infrastructure</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/08/12/using-ansible-to-provision-your-pure-storage-infrastructure/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/08/12/using-ansible-to-provision-your-pure-storage-infrastructure/</guid><description>&lt;p>I mentioned previously that there are many things I love about the Pure Storage Flasharray, but one of my favorite is how easy it is to integrate into different automation solutions. In this blog I will cover how to use Ansible to provision your Pure Storage Infrastructure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using Terraform to Provision your Pure Storage Infrastructure</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/08/06/using-terraform-to-provision-your-pure-storage-infrastructure/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/08/06/using-terraform-to-provision-your-pure-storage-infrastructure/</guid><description>&lt;p>There are many things I love about the Pure Storage Flasharray, but one of my favorite is how easy it is to integrate into different automation solutions. In this blog I will cover how to use Terraform to provision your Pure Storage Infrastructure. This will be the first post of many that show how easy it is to accomplish the same task using multiple automation methods.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What's New in the Pure Storage vRealize Orchestrator Plugin 3.5</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/whats-new-purestorage-vro-35/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/whats-new-purestorage-vro-35/</guid><description>&lt;p>Released on July 30, 2020 the latest vRO plugin for vRealize 7.x is here!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using Terraform to Deploy the Pure1 VM Analytics Collector</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/06/30/using-terraform-to-deploy-the-pure1-vm-analytics-collector/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 07:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/06/30/using-terraform-to-deploy-the-pure1-vm-analytics-collector/</guid><description>&lt;p>Pure1 VM Analytics is a great tool to have in your environment. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to even have a Pure Storage array, but it makes it even better! Back in 2019 the collector was converted to an OVA format and has been much simpler to deploy. You can deploy it through the UI or even Powershell. With the latest update to the Terraform vSphere provider we can now deploy OVA&amp;rsquo;s, so lets jump in to see how we can deploy the VM Analytics collector!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using the VMware Event Broker Appliance to Automatically Expand a Pure Storage FlashArray Datastore</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/using-veba-to-expand-pure-datastore/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/using-veba-to-expand-pure-datastore/</guid><description>&lt;p>Something we get asked quite often it seems here at Pure Storage, is can we automatically expand a datastore when it gets full? The answer is yes! With all of the integrations with automation platformsm, Pure Storage Arrays have many options. This blog will cover how to handle this with the VMware Event Broker Appliance (VEBA)!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Configuring vRealize Orchestrator to use Pure1 Integration</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/06/05/configuring-vrealize-orchestrator-to-use-pure1-integration/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/06/05/configuring-vrealize-orchestrator-to-use-pure1-integration/</guid><description>&lt;p>The more I play with our integrations the more I am impressed. My latest project within vRealize Orchestrator had me utilizing our Pure1 integration. This post will cover how to generate the needed pieces to configure the Pure1 Integration within vRO.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Unable to Provision a vVol Hard Disk on a VM Located on VMFS Datastore</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/06/02/unable-to-provision-a-vvol-hard-disk-on-a-vm-located-on-vmfs-datastore/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/06/02/unable-to-provision-a-vvol-hard-disk-on-a-vm-located-on-vmfs-datastore/</guid><description>&lt;p>An interesting issue came in from one of our customers that they were unable to provision a new vVol Disk on a VM that was based on a VMFS Datastore. After some troubleshooting it seems there was a regression which no longer makes this available in the UI. Take a look at this blog post on how I will cover a workaround.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What's New in the 4.3.1 Pure Storage vSphere Client Plugin</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/05/26/whats-new-in-the-4.3.1-pure-storage-vsphere-client-plugin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/05/26/whats-new-in-the-4.3.1-pure-storage-vsphere-client-plugin/</guid><description>&lt;p>In May 2020 Pure Storage released the latest version of their plugin version 4.3.1! This post will explore what&amp;rsquo;s new in this release!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Running vVols in VMware Cloud on AWS (VMC) on Pure Storage Cloud Block Store (CBS) on AWS</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/running-vvol-on-vmc-on-cbs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/running-vvol-on-vmc-on-cbs/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another post of a cool project this week. With the tools we have available during our hackathon it was asked if we could run vVols in VMware Cloud on AWS. Because of the locked down nature of VMC we could not run vVols directly on that cluster, but I did find a way that we could. Dive into this blog post to see how vVols run on CBS.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What's New in the Pure Storage vRealize Operations Management Pack 3.0</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/04/24/whats-new-in-the-pure-storage-vrealize-operations-management-pack-3.0/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/04/24/whats-new-in-the-pure-storage-vrealize-operations-management-pack-3.0/</guid><description>&lt;p>Released on April 15, 2020 the long awaited Pure Storage vRealize Operations Management Pack 3.0 is here!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What's New in the 4.3.0 Pure Storage vSphere Client Plugin</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/04/21/whats-new-in-the-4.3.0-pure-storage-vsphere-client-plugin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/04/21/whats-new-in-the-4.3.0-pure-storage-vsphere-client-plugin/</guid><description>&lt;p>On April 2, 2020 Pure Storage released the latest version of their plugin version 4.3.0! This post will explore the latest features in this release!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Replacing the Pure Storage FlashArray VASA Certificate</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/04/01/replacing-the-pure-storage-flasharray-vasa-certificate/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/04/01/replacing-the-pure-storage-flasharray-vasa-certificate/</guid><description>&lt;p>Maintaining Certificates in your environments is an important thing to do to make connections between your client and server are encrypted. With this blog we will go over how to replace your Pure Storage FlashArray Certificate for the vStorage APIs for Storage Awareness (VASA) using a Microsoft Certificate Authority.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Replacing the Pure Storage FlashArray Management Certificate</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/03/31/replacing-the-pure-storage-flasharray-management-certificate/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/03/31/replacing-the-pure-storage-flasharray-management-certificate/</guid><description>&lt;p>Maintaining Certificates in your environments is an important thing to do to make connections between your client and server are encrypted. With this blog we will go over how to replace your Pure Storage FlashArray Management Certificate using a Microsoft Certificate Authority.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Configuring and Using the Pure Storage vSphere Plugin with Pure1 Authentication</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/03/25/configuring-and-using-the-pure-storage-vsphere-plugin-with-pure1-authentication/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/03/25/configuring-and-using-the-pure-storage-vsphere-plugin-with-pure1-authentication/</guid><description>&lt;p>Beginning with version 4.2.0 the Pure Storage vSphere Client Plugin had a whole slew of new features added, one of those features was the ability to integrate authentication with Pure1 allowing fleet registration of all your Pure Storage Arrays among other things. This does require a slight change on how you would normally register your arrays in the plugin, so lets take a look at how we can accomplish this!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using vRealize Automation with the Pure Storage vRealize Orchestrator Plugin</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/03/20/using-vrealize-automation-with-the-pure-storage-vrealize-orchestrator-plugin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/03/20/using-vrealize-automation-with-the-pure-storage-vrealize-orchestrator-plugin/</guid><description>&lt;p>Moving forward with Automation, we will now expand our horizons past vRealize Orchestrator (vRO) into vRealize Automation (vRA)! Our integration with vRA utilizes the vRO Plugin and allows users to self-provision their infrastructure using all the goodness included with vRA such as blueprints, approval workflows and reservations. Lets Dive in and take a look!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using the Pure Storage vRealize Orchestrator Plugin</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/03/16/using-the-pure-storage-vrealize-orchestrator-plugin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/03/16/using-the-pure-storage-vrealize-orchestrator-plugin/</guid><description>&lt;p>Adding to the series of VMware and Pure Storage blogs is Automation! When it comes to automating your VMware Environment with Pure Storage we have a vRO Plugin for you! Dive in and take a look at how you can get your environment automated.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using the Pure Storage vRealize Operations Management Pack</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/03/10/using-the-pure-storage-vrealize-operations-management-pack/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/03/10/using-the-pure-storage-vrealize-operations-management-pack/</guid><description>&lt;p>When it comes to monitoring your Pure Storage environment, Pure1 is an amazing tool. However, some customers have an investment in the VMware vRealize Suite and wish to look at some of the Pure Storage Array information within their vRealize Operations environment.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using the Pure Storage vSphere Plugin</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/03/05/using-the-pure-storage-vsphere-plugin/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/03/05/using-the-pure-storage-vsphere-plugin/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome back! If you followed my previous post on Installing and Updating the Pure Storage vSphere Plugin, you may be wondering well What&amp;rsquo;s Next? Now its time to use it, which will empower your VMware Administrators to be awesome Pure Storage Administrators without ever needing to login to the Pure Storage UI!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Installing and Updating the Pure Storage vSphere Plugin</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/03/03/installing-and-updating-the-pure-storage-vsphere-plugin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/03/03/installing-and-updating-the-pure-storage-vsphere-plugin/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to the first of many Pure Storage blogs. As I get ramped up with the latest information I plan to do a series of getting started with Pure Storage features. These blogs will cover things such as the vSphere Client (HTML5) Plugin, FlashArray, FlashBlade and integrations with other VMware products. First up is learning to install and update the Pure Storage vSphere Client Plugin.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Back to Work, I'm Going to</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/02/12/back-to-work-im-going-to/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/02/12/back-to-work-im-going-to/</guid><description>When the unfortunate reduction in force (RIF) struck in January at VMware, I was in disbelief and didn&amp;rsquo;t even know where to start. Over the past two years I had the amazing opportunity to not only present to customers and partners in places I never imagined, but the ability to be an internal subject matter expert and create some amazing content. VMware is an amazing place to work and the relationships I&amp;rsquo;ve made and my impact to the products are beyond things I thought I could ever accomplish.</description></item><item><title>Using PureStorage Powershell to Configure SysLog Servers</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2016/03/14/using-purestorage-powershell-to-configure-syslog-servers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2016/03/14/using-purestorage-powershell-to-configure-syslog-servers/</guid><description>Currently working on the final steps of getting our new equipment configured. The next step was to configure Syslog on all of our Pure Arrays. Another reason to script this task! Easily populate your arrays and server and at the click of a button you can configure all your arrays easily.
Pre-Requsites PureStorage Powershell SDK Link to Script Set-PureStorageSyslog.ps1 Preparing to Execute the Script The script is pretty straight forward, just need to define a few variables seen below and then you execute the script.</description></item></channel></rss>