<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Lifecycle on davidstamen</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/tags/lifecycle/</link><description>Recent content in Lifecycle on davidstamen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2008–2018, Steve Francia and the Hugo Authors; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidstamen.com/tags/lifecycle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Handling the Lifecycle of a vCenter HA Environment</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2019/07/30/handling-the-lifecycle-of-a-vcenter-ha-environment/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2019/07/30/handling-the-lifecycle-of-a-vcenter-ha-environment/</guid><description>vSphere 6.5 first introduced vCenter HA and since its inception has been deployed in many environments. When it comes to upgrading or updating your vCenter HA environment there are some specific considerations. If you have wondered what it takes to handle the lifecycle of a vCenter HA enabled vCenter Server, keep reading!
vCenter HA Overview vCenter HA has seen wide adoption as customers wish to provide provide high availability for their vCenter Server.</description></item><item><title>What's New with Auto Deploy in vSphere 6.7 U1</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2018/10/18/whats-new-with-auto-deploy-in-vsphere-6.7-u1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2018/10/18/whats-new-with-auto-deploy-in-vsphere-6.7-u1/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you havent heard vSphere 6.7 U1 is now out and is loaded with all new features! If you have used 6.7 GA you may have noticed the Auto Deploy functionality did not yet make it into the long awaited vSphere Client. With vCenter Server 6.7 U1 we now have feature parity and this means Auto Deploy has been added to the vSphere Client. Lets jump in and see some of the new functionality that has been included.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>