<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>vSphere 7.0 on davidstamen</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/tags/vsphere-7.0/</link><description>Recent content in vSphere 7.0 on davidstamen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2008–2018, Steve Francia and the Hugo Authors; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 08:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidstamen.com/tags/vsphere-7.0/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Unable to Sync vLCM Updates - Error: 'integrity.fault.HostPatchInvalidVendorCode'.</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/unable-to-sync-vlcm-update-70u1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/unable-to-sync-vlcm-update-70u1/</guid><description>&lt;p>After upgrading my vCenter Server to the latest vSphere 7.0 Update 1, I was unable to see ESXi 7.0 Update 1 Image. When I attempted to sync the updates I got the error &amp;ldquo;Download patch definitions task failed while syncing depots. Error: &amp;lsquo;integrity.fault.HostPatchInvalidVendorCode&amp;rsquo;.&amp;rdquo; Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look how we can resolve this issue and be able to sync the latest updates.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Updating the vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) with PowerCLI - Revisited</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/06/22/updating-the-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-with-powercli-revisited/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/06/22/updating-the-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-with-powercli-revisited/</guid><description>In previous blogs, I covered how to update your VCSA using PowerCLI and with Postman. I also had multiple code sessions at VMworld 2019 where I got great feedback on the module. It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I have looked at the module, and time has passed so I thought it was due for an update. The module will no longer need to be manually imported, it is now located in the Powershell Gallery!</description></item><item><title>Patching the vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) using the REST API - Part 2 (PowerCLI Module)</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2019/01/31/patching-the-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-using-the-rest-api-part-2-powershell-module/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2019/01/31/patching-the-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-using-the-rest-api-part-2-powershell-module/</guid><description>Previously I covered how to use the VCSA Installer to do a scripted upgrade and then I covered Patching the vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) using the REST API - Part 1 (Postman Collection) However, after learning recently how to call API&amp;rsquo;s from Powershell I thought to myself, why not write a Powershell Module for this?
Introduction Using tools such as Postman can make it utilizing API&amp;rsquo;s a bit easier, but you still need to be familiar with a separate tool or UI.</description></item></channel></rss>