<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vsphereupgrade on davidstamen.com</title>
    <link>http://davidstamen.com/tags/vsphereupgrade/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vsphereupgrade on davidstamen.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://davidstamen.com/tags/vsphereupgrade/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Why and How To Upgrade to vSphere 6.7 U1</title>
      <link>http://davidstamen.com/2018/10/11/why-and-how-to-upgrade-to-vsphere-6.7-u1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidstamen.com/2018/10/11/why-and-how-to-upgrade-to-vsphere-6.7-u1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;vSphere 6.7 Update 1 is finally here! Lets jump in and find out how and why to upgrade!
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating the Upgrade of the Virtual Distributed Switch</title>
      <link>http://davidstamen.com/2018/10/08/automating-the-upgrade-of-the-virtual-distributed-switch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 08:02:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidstamen.com/2018/10/08/automating-the-upgrade-of-the-virtual-distributed-switch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are on the home stretch of our Automating your vSphere Upgrade blog series. The final step of completing our upgrade will be upgrading our Virtual Distributed Switch (VDS). When upgrading your VDS on vSphere 6.7 the version is actually 6.6 (we will cover the details later). Please make sure prior to upgrading your VDS to 6.6 all ESXi hosts have been upgraded to ESXi 6.7, if you still have hosts on ESXi 6.5 you will only be able to upgrade to version 6.5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating Migration of VMFS-5 to VMFS-6 Datastores</title>
      <link>http://davidstamen.com/2018/10/07/automating-migration-of-vmfs-5-to-vmfs-6-datastores/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 08:13:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidstamen.com/2018/10/07/automating-migration-of-vmfs-5-to-vmfs-6-datastores/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Next up in our Automating your vSphere Upgrade blog series is your VMFS Datastore. vSphere 6.5 and vSphere 6.7 both support the latest VMFS-6. Once all of your ESXi hosts that are connected to the VMFS-5 datastore have been upgraded to vSphere 6.5 or vSphere 6.7 you can then proceed to migrate your datastore to VMFS-6.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating Upgrade of VMware Tools and VM Compatibility</title>
      <link>http://davidstamen.com/2018/10/06/automating-upgrade-of-vmware-tools-and-vm-compatibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 08:25:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidstamen.com/2018/10/06/automating-upgrade-of-vmware-tools-and-vm-compatibility/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Next up in our Automating your vSphere Upgrade blog series is your VMware Tools and VM Compatibility. Upgrading these both have different requirements so we will cover when and how you should upgrade your VMware Tools and VM compatibility in the below post.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading Platform Services Controller and VCenter Server via the CLI Installer</title>
      <link>http://davidstamen.com/2018/10/05/upgrading-platform-services-controller-and-vcenter-server-via-the-cli-installer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 09:08:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidstamen.com/2018/10/05/upgrading-platform-services-controller-and-vcenter-server-via-the-cli-installer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first topic we will cover in our Automating your vSphere Upgrade series is updating our core infrastructure. Upgrading Platform Services Controller(PSC)  and vCenter Server via the CLI installer. In our workshops one of the common things I hear is that most folks aren&amp;rsquo;t using the CLI based tools that have been included in the installer. I am a huge fan of these as they make migrations and upgrades seamless&amp;ndash;especially when having to perform the task if you have multiple PSC&amp;rsquo;s and vCenter Servers. Using the CLI tools don’t have to be intimidating, as we go through this blog we will cover some how-to&amp;rsquo;s and benefits of using the CLI based approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>