<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Windows on davidstamen</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/tags/windows/</link><description>Recent content in Windows on davidstamen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2008–2018, Steve Francia and the Hugo Authors; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 08:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidstamen.com/tags/windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using Bicep to Deploy a Microsoft SQL on Azure VM with Cloud Block Store Volumes</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2023/05/17/using-bicep-to-deploy-a-microsoft-sql-on-azure-vm-with-cloud-block-store-volumes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2023/05/17/using-bicep-to-deploy-a-microsoft-sql-on-azure-vm-with-cloud-block-store-volumes/</guid><description>&lt;p>This blog will showcase how to deploy an Azure VM that has a configured Microsoft SQL Instance that is connected to a Cloud Block Store (CBS) volume. I have previously showcased VM &amp;amp; CBS deployments with both Powershell and Terraform, but its time to bring it to a new language!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using Bicep to Deploy an Azure Virtual Machine</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2023/05/15/using-bicep-to-deploy-an-azure-virtual-machine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2023/05/15/using-bicep-to-deploy-an-azure-virtual-machine/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to another blog on Automation! This one will be focused on deploying resources in Azure using Bicep. Follow along to understand what Bicep is and my thoughts on it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deploying a EC2 Instance with PowerShell to AWS</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-ec2-using-powershell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-ec2-using-powershell/</guid><description>&lt;p>Previously, I covered how to Deploy and Bootstrap an EC2 Instance in AWS using Terraform. Not everyone may use Terraform, but quite a few people are using PowerShell today. Lets take a Look at how we can use AWSPowerShell to deploy an EC2 instance in AWS.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deploying a Windows Azure VM with Hashicorp Terraform to Microsoft Azure</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-avm-using-terraform/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-avm-using-terraform/</guid><description>&lt;p>As a followup to my previous post on Automating EC2 deployments, I figured why not show how this can also be done with Microsoft Azure? Check out how to launch an Azure VM instance and run some scripts to customize your installation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deploying a Windows EC2 Instance with Hashicorp Terraform and Vault to AWS</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-ec2-using-terraform-vault/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-ec2-using-terraform-vault/</guid><description>&lt;p>As part of demonstrating our products to customers, I tend to reprovision EC2 instances to show how easy it is to mount data in AWS to Cloud Block Store. After doing this manually a little too often, I figured why not automate it? Check out this blog on how I use Terraform to deploy a EC2 instance and configure it for in-guest iSCSI.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using Powershell to Create Windows SMB Shares</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2016/08/09/using-powershell-to-create-windows-smb-shares/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2016/08/09/using-powershell-to-create-windows-smb-shares/</guid><description>I have been knee deep in migrations, so after clicking through a few times to create clustered file shares, I finally decided to script them. Here is that script I thought I would share. Thanksfully there was the NTFSSecurity module published by microsoft that makes permissions a breeze. You can get more details by viewing the module page.
Pre-Requsites NTFS Security Module Link to Script Create-SMBShare.ps1 Preparing to Execute the Script Fill in the appropriate variables, and execute the script.</description></item><item><title>Using Vagrant to Deploy a 2012R2 DHCP Failover Cluster</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2015/10/01/using-vagrant-to-deploy-a-2012r2-dhcp-failover-cluster/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2015/10/01/using-vagrant-to-deploy-a-2012r2-dhcp-failover-cluster/</guid><description>So I am in the process of rolling out a new 2012R2 DHCP Server Cluster, and I thought i would share my scripts with the community.
I have also rolled it into a Vagrant package so you can easily test it on your own, and execute the scripts by themselves against your environment to deploy.
Here is a link to the GitHub repository containing all the code.
The code is also fairly simple, it pulls in data from a few .</description></item><item><title>Unable to Install .NET 3.5 on Server 2012R2</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2014/09/11/unable-to-install-net-3-5-on-server-2012r2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2014/09/11/unable-to-install-net-3-5-on-server-2012r2/</guid><description>So upon trying to install .Net 3.5 on a new server today it would not allow me to, it kept telling me the source files were unavailable even after pointing to source directly to multiple ISO&amp;rsquo;s and copied the files locally.
Upon further research I stumbled across this microsoft KB article and used it to ultimately find my fix. KB2734782
Here are the full steps I followed to get .NET installed.</description></item></channel></rss>