<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VRealize Automation on davidstamen</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/tags/vrealize-automation/</link><description>Recent content in VRealize Automation on davidstamen</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2008–2018, Steve Francia and the Hugo Authors; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidstamen.com/tags/vrealize-automation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using vRealize Automation 8.x with the Pure Storage vRealize Orchestrator Plugin</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2021/02/18/using-vrealize-automation-8.x-with-the-pure-storage-vrealize-orchestrator-plugin/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2021/02/18/using-vrealize-automation-8.x-with-the-pure-storage-vrealize-orchestrator-plugin/</guid><description>&lt;p>Previously I explained how to use the vRealize Orchestrator Plugin 3.5 with vRealize Orchestrator and Automation 7.x. Back in November of 2020 we released the latest update to our vRO workflow package 4.0 which introduced support for vRealize Automation/Orchestrator 8.x! Our integration with vRA utilizes the vRO Plugin and allows users to self-provision their infrastructure using all the goodness included with vRA such as blueprints, approval workflows and reservations. Lets Dive in and take a look!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>vExpert Cloud Management 2020 Award</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/04/07/vexpert-cloud-management-2020-award/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/04/07/vexpert-cloud-management-2020-award/</guid><description>&lt;p>VMware and their vExpert Program has announced the vExpert Sub-Program announcements and I am glad to see I have been accepted into the vExpert Cloud Management group!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using vRealize Automation with the Pure Storage vRealize Orchestrator Plugin</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/03/20/using-vrealize-automation-with-the-pure-storage-vrealize-orchestrator-plugin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/03/20/using-vrealize-automation-with-the-pure-storage-vrealize-orchestrator-plugin/</guid><description>&lt;p>Moving forward with Automation, we will now expand our horizons past vRealize Orchestrator (vRO) into vRealize Automation (vRA)! Our integration with vRA utilizes the vRO Plugin and allows users to self-provision their infrastructure using all the goodness included with vRA such as blueprints, approval workflows and reservations. Lets Dive in and take a look!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>