<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VMware on davidstamen.com</title>
    <link>/categories/vmware/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VMware on davidstamen.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/vmware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Patching the vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) using the REST API - Part 2 (Powershell Module)</title>
      <link>/2018/12/26/patching-the-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-using-the-rest-api-part-2-powershell-module/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/12/26/patching-the-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-using-the-rest-api-part-2-powershell-module/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Previously I covered how to use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.vmware.com/vsphere/2018/09/upgrading-platform-services-controller-and-vcenter-server-via-the-cli-installer.html&#34;&gt;VCSA Installer to do a scripted upgrade&lt;/a&gt; and then I covered &lt;a href=&#34;https://davidstamen.com/2018/12/20/patching-the-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-using-the-rest-api/&#34;&gt;Patching the vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) using the REST API - Part 1 (Postman Collection)&lt;/a&gt; However, after learning recently how to call API&amp;rsquo;s from Powershell I thought to myself, why not write a Powershell Module for this?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patching the vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) using the REST API - Part 1 (Postman Collection)</title>
      <link>/2018/12/20/patching-the-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-using-the-rest-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/12/20/patching-the-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-using-the-rest-api/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am a huge fan of Automating the vSphere Lifecycle process. The next step I wanted to cover was patching the vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) using the REST API.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unable to Update to vCenter Server 6.5 U2d on VCSA</title>
      <link>/2018/11/19/unable-to-update-to-vcenter-server-6.5-u2d-on-vcsa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/11/19/unable-to-update-to-vcenter-server-6.5-u2d-on-vcsa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When trying to update your vSphere 6.5 environment to vSphere 6.5u2d it may show that there are no available updates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading to VMware vSphere 6.7 eBook - Now Available</title>
      <link>/2018/11/19/upgrading-to-vmware-vsphere-6.7-ebook-now-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/11/19/upgrading-to-vmware-vsphere-6.7-ebook-now-available/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am proud to announce availability of the new Upgrading to VMware vSphere 6.7 eBook.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vSphere Update Manager 6.7 Unable to Scan Cluster</title>
      <link>/2018/10/25/vsphere-update-manager-6.7-unable-to-scan-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/25/vsphere-update-manager-6.7-unable-to-scan-cluster/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently deployed a couple new vSphere 6.7 labs and was having some issues running Check Compliance within Update Manager.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld EU - Sessions and Events</title>
      <link>/2018/10/24/vmworld-eu-2018-sessions-events/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/24/vmworld-eu-2018-sessions-events/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;VMworld EU is around the corner and just like VMworld US I will be quite busy! If you are interested in where to find me, look below to see some my planned sessions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s New with Auto Deploy in vSphere 6.7 U1</title>
      <link>/2018/10/18/whats-new-with-auto-deploy-in-vsphere-6.7-u1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/18/whats-new-with-auto-deploy-in-vsphere-6.7-u1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you havent heard vSphere 6.7 U1 is now out and is loaded with all new features! If you have used 6.7 GA you may have noticed the Auto Deploy functionality did not yet make it into the long awaited vSphere Client. With vCenter Server 6.7 U1 we now have feature parity and this means Auto Deploy has been added to the vSphere Client. Lets jump in and see some of the new functionality that has been included.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why and How To Upgrade to vSphere 6.7 U1</title>
      <link>/2018/10/11/why-and-how-to-upgrade-to-vsphere-6.7-u1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/11/why-and-how-to-upgrade-to-vsphere-6.7-u1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;vSphere 6.7 Update 1 is finally here! Lets jump in and find out how and why to upgrade!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating the Upgrade of the Virtual Distributed Switch</title>
      <link>/2018/10/08/automating-the-upgrade-of-the-virtual-distributed-switch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 08:02:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/08/automating-the-upgrade-of-the-virtual-distributed-switch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are on the home stretch of our Automating your vSphere Upgrade blog series. The final step of completing our upgrade will be upgrading our Virtual Distributed Switch (VDS). When upgrading your VDS on vSphere 6.7 the version is actually 6.6 (we will cover the details later). Please make sure prior to upgrading your VDS to 6.6 all ESXi hosts have been upgraded to ESXi 6.7, if you still have hosts on ESXi 6.5 you will only be able to upgrade to version 6.5.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating Migration of VMFS-5 to VMFS-6 Datastores</title>
      <link>/2018/10/07/automating-migration-of-vmfs-5-to-vmfs-6-datastores/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 08:13:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/07/automating-migration-of-vmfs-5-to-vmfs-6-datastores/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Next up in our Automating your vSphere Upgrade blog series is your VMFS Datastore. vSphere 6.5 and vSphere 6.7 both support the latest VMFS-6. Once all of your ESXi hosts that are connected to the VMFS-5 datastore have been upgraded to vSphere 6.5 or vSphere 6.7 you can then proceed to migrate your datastore to VMFS-6.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating Upgrade of VMware Tools and VM Compatibility</title>
      <link>/2018/10/06/automating-upgrade-of-vmware-tools-and-vm-compatibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 08:25:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/06/automating-upgrade-of-vmware-tools-and-vm-compatibility/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Next up in our Automating your vSphere Upgrade blog series is your VMware Tools and VM Compatibility. Upgrading these both have different requirements so we will cover when and how you should upgrade your VMware Tools and VM compatibility in the below post.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading Platform Services Controller and vCenter Server via the CLI Installer</title>
      <link>/2018/10/05/upgrading-platform-services-controller-and-vcenter-server-via-the-cli-installer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 09:08:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/05/upgrading-platform-services-controller-and-vcenter-server-via-the-cli-installer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first topic we will cover in our Automating your vSphere Upgrade series is updating our core infrastructure. Upgrading Platform Services Controller(PSC)  and vCenter Server via the CLI installer. In our workshops one of the common things I hear is that most folks aren&amp;rsquo;t using the CLI based tools that have been included in the installer. I am a huge fan of these as they make migrations and upgrades seamless&amp;ndash;especially when having to perform the task if you have multiple PSC&amp;rsquo;s and vCenter Servers. Using the CLI tools don’t have to be intimidating, as we go through this blog we will cover some how-to&amp;rsquo;s and benefits of using the CLI based approach.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>L1 Terminal Fault (L1TF) Patching Considerations</title>
      <link>/2018/08/15/l1-terminal-fault-l1tf-patching-considerations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 10:47:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/15/l1-terminal-fault-l1tf-patching-considerations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday August 14th, Intel Released their news on the latest vulnerability &lt;strong&gt;L1 Terminal Fault (L1TF) or ForeShadow&lt;/strong&gt;. In response to this VMware released vSphere patches to address the issues. Since then I have seen quite a few threads come up and thought i would address them from a patching perspective.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2018 - Sessions and Events</title>
      <link>/2018/07/18/vmworld-2018-sessions-events/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 10:19:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/07/18/vmworld-2018-sessions-events/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This will be my first VMworld attending as an employee and quite a bit of things will be going on. Just in case anyone was interesting in vSphere Upgrades I wanted to share out some key sessions that I recommend including my own.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patching your vCenter Server Appliance from 6.7 to 6.7a</title>
      <link>/2018/05/23/patching-your-vcenter-server-appliance-from-6.7-to-6.7a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 12:45:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/23/patching-your-vcenter-server-appliance-from-6.7-to-6.7a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On May 22nd we released the first update to our vCenter Server 6.7 version, 6.7a. I will let you know how you can patch your 6.7 GA vCenter Server to 6.7a.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading to VMware vSphere 6.7</title>
      <link>/2018/04/17/upgrading-to-vmware-vsphere-6.7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 08:32:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/17/upgrading-to-vmware-vsphere-6.7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s finally out! vSphere 6.7 is the next major release of VMware&amp;rsquo;s virtualization software. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using 6.7 through the &lt;a href=&#34;https://secure.vmware.com/43478_vSphere_Beta_Reg&#34;&gt;vSphere Beta Program&lt;/a&gt; and testing even newer features in my current role. I am here to talk to you about planning your vSphere upgrade and some planning and considerations you should have when going to the latest release.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reconfigure HA - The object &#39;vim.Datastore:datastore-XXXX&#39; has already been deleted or has not been completely created</title>
      <link>/2018/01/19/reconfigure-ha-the-object-vim.datastoredatastore-xxxx-has-already-been-deleted-or-has-not-been-completely-created/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 10:27:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/19/reconfigure-ha-the-object-vim.datastoredatastore-xxxx-has-already-been-deleted-or-has-not-been-completely-created/</guid>
      <description>Another lovely Friday starting off with strange issues, when taking a host out of standard maintenance we noticed that HA would not reconfigure, and kept saying The object &amp;lsquo;vim.Datastore:datastore-1131&amp;rsquo; has already been deleted or has not been completely created. This was strange because no other hosts had this issue.
I proceeded to follow standard troubleshooting steps, reconfigure HA&amp;hellip;same issue&amp;hellip;.disable HA for entire cluster and re-enable&amp;hellip;..same issue&amp;hellip;whoops thats not good!
First step, check what luns are available to the cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vRA 7.3 - Using Active Directory Policies</title>
      <link>/2017/08/vra-73-using-active-directory-policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 14:00:46 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/08/vra-73-using-active-directory-policies/</guid>
      <description>So it seems to be that time of year again with new projects coming around. This time its all about vRA. This is probably my first of many blogs to come about things I have come across.
My question today was how do I pre-create a computer AD account, join a device to the domain and then clean it up when the machine is destroyed.
Turns out this is super simple in vRealize Automation 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vCenter 6.5U1 Update Issues with VCHA Advanced Deployment</title>
      <link>/2017/08/02/vcenter-6.5u1-update-issues-with-vcha-advanced-deployment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 16:08:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/08/02/vcenter-6.5u1-update-issues-with-vcha-advanced-deployment/</guid>
      <description>vSphere 6.5U1 was released on July 27th. This is an incremental update a lot of people wait for before upgrading from a previous version. I have been lucky to have been running on vSphere 6.5 for quite some time and have been enjoying it very much.
Obviously we never upgrade production first, if we can help it. I decided to attempt an upgrade on one of our QA vCenters that was deployed using the VCHA Advanced workflow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using PowerCLI to Add vRealize Operations License Key</title>
      <link>/2017/07/27/using-powercli-to-add-vrealize-operations-license-key/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/07/27/using-powercli-to-add-vrealize-operations-license-key/</guid>
      <description>I have been working on doing a vCenter Consolidation Project. This included migrating our systems to a new vRealize Operations Server. This particular one included 73 different vSOM keys, and as you may know there is currently no way to enter in multiple keys at a time. I reached out to Kyle Ruddy and he informed me there is an API to do this, and that started my adventure to get this working.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using PowerCLI to Set vCenter Permissions on Datacenter</title>
      <link>/2017/04/17/using-powercli-to-set-vcenter-permissions-on-datacenter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/04/17/using-powercli-to-set-vcenter-permissions-on-datacenter/</guid>
      <description>I have been working on doing a vCenter Consolidation Project. This has meant recreating multiple permissions groups. I couldnt find an easy way to apply permissions at a datacenter so I updated this script to be used.
Pre-Requsites  VMware PowerCLI  Link to Script  Set-vCenterPermissions.ps1 permissions.csv  Preparing to Execute the Script The script is pretty straight forward, just need to update columns in the CSV such as Datacenter, Group and Role.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vSphere 6.5 - Updating Appliance configured with vCenter HA</title>
      <link>/2017/02/03/vsphere-65-updating-appliance-configured-with-vcenter-ha/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/02/03/vsphere-65-updating-appliance-configured-with-vcenter-ha/</guid>
      <description>Warning: A few others and myself have noticed that when updating a VCHA Cluster to 6.5U1 it resets the hostname to localhost.localdomain stopping vCenter Web Client from Loading. It seems to be isolated to Advanced Deployments and not Basic. I would recommend destroying your VCHA Cluster, updating, then redeploying in this scenario. Warning2: It also seems that if you try to redeploy VCHA Advanced after an upgrade, it still resets the hostname, I have a case opened and will update here as neccessary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vSphere 6.5 - vCenter HA Health Degraded due to Password Expiration</title>
      <link>/2017/02/01/vcenter-ha-health-degraded-due-to-password-expiration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/02/01/vcenter-ha-health-degraded-due-to-password-expiration/</guid>
      <description>One of my favorite new features of vSphere 6.5 is definately vCenter HA. I was checking out alerts when I noticed i had an alarm for vCenter HA being degraded.
Looking through the GUI, I was unable to find anything in regards to why the Health was a warning and why the components would not sync. Then I remembered a previous case I had opened for VCHA.
There is a log file located in /var/log/vmware/vcha</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional Branding of vSphere Web Client Logon Page</title>
      <link>/2017/01/19/functional-branding-of-vsphere-web-client-logon-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/01/19/functional-branding-of-vsphere-web-client-logon-page/</guid>
      <description>I had a use case I wanted to investigate in regards to the new VCHA that is part of VMware vCenter Server 6.5. One thing I noticed, is when you have VCHA configured, there is no way to know which node of the HA cluster you are connecting to without being logged on.
As people have noted before William Lam&amp;rsquo;s - How to Customize Webclient Login UI
I figured since I am using the embedded SSO, I could update the login page to show any information for that particular node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the VMware Content Libray Assistant Fling</title>
      <link>/2016/12/29/using-the-vmware-content-libray-assistant-fling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/12/29/using-the-vmware-content-libray-assistant-fling/</guid>
      <description>So VMware Flings have been on a roll recently. They have released what they call &amp;ldquo;VMware Content Library Assistant.&amp;rdquo; This is a java based CLI app, that connects to your vCenter and searchers for your templates and then automatically creates and uploads them.
You can find the fling at the following URL&amp;hellip;https://labs.vmware.com/flings/vsphere-content-library-assistant)
Once you download the fling, you can just run the following command.
java -jar sphere-content-library-assistant-1.0.jar -s servername -u username -p password  In my case my java home isn&amp;rsquo;t setup on my mac so I had to run the following command to get it to work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vSphere 6.5 - vCenter HA (VCHA) Issues</title>
      <link>/2016/11/21/vsphere-65-vcha-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/11/21/vsphere-65-vcha-issues/</guid>
      <description>So as everyone has probably seen, vSphere 6.5 is now GA. One of the features i have been waiting for the most is vCenter HA. I have spent some time trying to get this working in my lab. Unfortunately after countless tries i was stuck. Thanks to folks in the vExpert Slack for helping me try to resolve this, but unfortunately this was a case for VMware Support.
Every time I would try to configure vCenter HA using the Advanced Wizard, I would get the following error.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vSphere 6.5 - New License Import from My VMware</title>
      <link>/2016/11/16/vsphere-65-new-license-import-from-myvmware/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/11/16/vsphere-65-new-license-import-from-myvmware/</guid>
      <description>So as everyone has probably seen, vSphere 6.5 is now GA. As usual right away I have upgraded the homelab and have already found a neat new feature.
When you are adding in your VMware licenses, you now have an option to Import License Keys Data&amp;hellip;
To start you need to generate a report from my.vmware.com.
 Log in and Navigate to Download Reports
 Click on the Available Reports dropdown, and select the Product Licenses, Details and History.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using PowerCLI to Get and Set DVS Traffic Shaping Settings</title>
      <link>/2016/04/21/using-powercli-to-get-and-set-dvs-traffic-shaping-settings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/04/21/using-powercli-to-get-and-set-dvs-traffic-shaping-settings/</guid>
      <description>I have been in process in configuring traffic shaping for multiple port groups. It seems with PowerCLI 6.3 R1 there are no native Powershell Cmdlets. Luckily I stumbled across @Lucd and his PowerCLI functions to manage these settings, i have put these into a script to mass get and set the settings for all port groups of a DVS&amp;rsquo;s.
Pre-Requsites  VMware PowerCLI  Link to Script  Get-VMwareTrafficShapingSettings.ps1 Set-VMwareTrafficShapingSettings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting Cisco ENIC and FNIC Drivers with VMware Update Manager 6.x</title>
      <link>/2016/04/08/troubleshooting-cisco-enic-and-fnic-drivers-with-vmware-update-manager-6x/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/04/08/troubleshooting-cisco-enic-and-fnic-drivers-with-vmware-update-manager-6x/</guid>
      <description>I have been having issues ever since I updated to vSphere 6.x getting the Cisco Drivers to properly update through VMware Update Manager(VUM). Every time I would run through a compliance check, they would always report they were up to date even when they were running an older version.
I have recently made a breakthrough working with VMware Support and stumbling through some old blogs. Cisco Support has been terrible on this issue and after repeated attempts to get this case escalated i think the 10th time is a charm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using PowerCLI to Install Host VIBs</title>
      <link>/2016/03/03/using-powercli-to-install-host-vibs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/03/03/using-powercli-to-install-host-vibs/</guid>
      <description>So currently Cisco has an issue with installing their ENIC and FNIC VIBs through Update Manager for ESXi 6.x. Until that is resolved I need to manually push out patches to these hosts. Obviously I do not want to do this manually, so I will be utilizing PowerCLI to accomplish this task.
Pre-Requsites  VMware PowerCLI  Link to Script  Install-HostVIB.ps1  Preparing to Execute the Script The script is pretty straight forward, just need to define a few variables seen below and then you execute the script.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using PowerCLI to Install Software in a Guest VM</title>
      <link>/2016/01/29/using-powercli-to-install-software-in-a-guest-vm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/01/29/using-powercli-to-install-software-in-a-guest-vm/</guid>
      <description>I have been constantly trying to figure out the best way to deploy updated agents to some of our virtual desktops. It isnt a large environment so I have no need for SCCM or other deployment tools, but its big enough having to RDP to each VM was a pain. I finally decided to bang out a script, and surprised how well it works.
Pre-Requsites  VMware PowerCLI  Link to Script  InstallVMSoftware.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using PowerCLI to Replicate Templates to Multiple Clusters</title>
      <link>/2016/01/26/using-powercli-to-replicate-templates-to-multiple-clusters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/01/26/using-powercli-to-replicate-templates-to-multiple-clusters/</guid>
      <description>We have multiple clusters within our vCenters that are defined as a rack. Each rack has its own storage, so storage is not shared between clusters. I needed to develop a way to easily replicate templates between clusters, so a local copy existed on each cluster to take advantage of VAAI.
I really wanted to utilize the vSphere Content Libary for these, but there is currently no publicly available documentation on how to deploy a VM from a Content Library via a Script.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unable to Boot EFI VM on ESXi FC Storage</title>
      <link>/2016/01/13/unable-to-boot-efi-vm-on-esxi-fc-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/01/13/unable-to-boot-efi-vm-on-esxi-fc-storage/</guid>
      <description>For the past week, I have been troubleshooting the strangest issue. I have been attempting to move some Windows 8.1 VM&amp;rsquo;s from our legacy datacenter(iSCSI) to our new datacenter(FC).
Whenever I would move the VM to our new DC, it would fail to boot properly. It would boot straight to Windows Recovery. If I moved the same VM to any other type of storage(NFS, iSCSI, Local) the VM would boot perfectly fine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading VCSA from 6.0 U1a to 6.0U1b using CLI</title>
      <link>/2016/01/12/upgrading-vcsa-from-60-u1a-to-60u1b/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/01/12/upgrading-vcsa-from-60-u1a-to-60u1b/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my post about upgrading your VMware vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) to 6.0 U1b.
This process is very straight forward. We will begin with updating our Platform Service Controllers (PSC) and then proceed with the vCenter Appliance.
 SSH to your Primary PSC. If you are currently in the bash shell, type appliancesh to switch shells to run the update. Run software-packages install &amp;ndash;url &amp;ndash;acceptEulas to download and install the packages from the VMware Repo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Host VIB&#39;s Using PowerCLI</title>
      <link>/2015/11/30/installing-host-vibs-using-powercli/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/11/30/installing-host-vibs-using-powercli/</guid>
      <description>Normally when i need to install and update a host VIB I use Update Manager. However there is currently a bug with Cisco&amp;rsquo;s latest enic/fnic drivers that wont let you install them via UM.
I had to run these updates on over 50 hosts and I really didn&amp;rsquo;t want to have to ssh and install it manually. Lucky I remember Brian Graf&amp;rsquo;s Host Client Install Fling and borrowed some of the code to come up with the below script.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using CLI to Manage DVS Host Uplinks</title>
      <link>/2015/11/30/using-cli-to-manage-dvs-host-uplinks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/11/30/using-cli-to-manage-dvs-host-uplinks/</guid>
      <description>Ever needed to modify a DVS uplink configuration from ESXi Shell? I am currently troubleshooting some issues with DVS uplinks no longer being assigned on reboot.
As a heads up. If you are doing this on ESXi 6.0.. don&amp;rsquo;t. It can cause an issue with the proxy DVS having different ID than the actual DVS causing my original issue, still working with VMware Support to find out more details.
After &amp;ldquo;Restoring Network Configuration&amp;rdquo; a few too many times, I finally realized I could just add the uplinks back via CLI until support can figure out why this is occurring, here are the details on how to manage the uplinks on a DVS via CLI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disconnected vNIC&#39;s?</title>
      <link>/2015/11/18/disconnected-vnics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/11/18/disconnected-vnics/</guid>
      <description>Ever wonder why a VM isn&amp;rsquo;t on the network?
I was working on deploying some test VM&amp;rsquo;s and for some reason all the VM&amp;rsquo;s that were cloned decided to start with the network disconnected, and the connect on power on was also not selected.
I decided to throw together this quick one-liner that will make sure every VM is set to start connected on power on and is currently connected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reusing Horizon View Desktop Names</title>
      <link>/2015/11/11/reusing-horizon-view-desktop-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/11/11/reusing-horizon-view-desktop-names/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever worked with a Horizon View pool with 10 VM&amp;rsquo;s and deleted 3 and it recreated as 11? May want to pay attention to learn how you can reuse view desktop names.
First you will need to connect to the ADAM database on one of your servers. Use KB2012377 for instructions.
To connect to the View ADAM database:
 Log in to one of the View Connection Servers as Domain Administrator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unregistering vSphere 6 VCSA from PSC</title>
      <link>/2015/10/13/unregistering-vsphere-6-vcsa-from-psc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/10/13/unregistering-vsphere-6-vcsa-from-psc/</guid>
      <description>So I am in the process of doing some vSphere 6 testing and needed to test a redeployment of one of my VCSA&amp;rsquo;s. The problem is when I went to redeploy it I got the following error.
Decoding the error, I pretty much figured that the object already existed in the SSO database and I needed to delete the existing object. Here is how you do that.
 Log in as root to the appliance shell of the Platform Services Controller appliance with which the vCenter Server Appliance is registered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using PowerCLI to Build Out vCenter</title>
      <link>/2015/10/08/using-powercli-to-build-out-vcenter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/10/08/using-powercli-to-build-out-vcenter/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to share this handy script i created when you have a need to build out a new vCenter.
This script can be extremely handy as it will take care of creating the datacenter, cluster, adding hosts, creating datastores and then applying the appropriate host profile. It is all done via CSV files so it is extremely customizable.
Files to modify to customize your configuration  createdatacenter.csv - Contains the name of the datacenter to create.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ESXi 5.5 Update 3a Released</title>
      <link>/2015/10/06/esxi-55-update-3a-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/10/06/esxi-55-update-3a-released/</guid>
      <description>ESXi 5.5 Update 3a and its associated patch have been released. If you have been following KB2133118 in regards to the the Snapshot Consolidation causing Virtual Machines to crash a fix is now available.
If you are currently running ESXi 5.5 U3 you can use update manager to install the patch.
If you are looking to install ESXi 5.5 U3 from scratch or update from a previous version you should make sure you update to 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ESXi 6.0 Update 1a Released</title>
      <link>/2015/10/06/esxi-60-update-1a-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/10/06/esxi-60-update-1a-released/</guid>
      <description>ESXi 6.0 Update 1a has been released. If you have been following KB2124669 in regards to the the NETDEV WATCHDOG issue causing an ESXi host to hang. The update is now available.
If you are currently running ESXi 6.0/6.0U1 you can use update manager to install the update.
If you are looking to install ESXi 6.0 U1 from scratch or update from a previous version you should make sure you update to use the latest ISO.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indexing your Horizon View Database</title>
      <link>/2015/09/30/indexing-your-horizon-view-database/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/09/30/indexing-your-horizon-view-database/</guid>
      <description>I am currently troubleshooting some issues with the Horizon event database having some performance issues. Working with support they pointed me to KB2094580.
By Default the view event database is not indexed. I was curious as to way I always had issues pulling up events in the Horizon View Administrative interface, but as soon as I followed the steps, it was almost immediate now, where i use to have to wait an extremely long time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading Horizon View Linux Desktop</title>
      <link>/2015/09/24/upgrading-horizon-view-linux-desktop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/09/24/upgrading-horizon-view-linux-desktop/</guid>
      <description>Horizon 6.2 is now available and Linux support has improved. Previously it was only supported on a limited set of older operating systems.
Originally when we deployed we had deployed Ubuntu 12.04, however now the newer kernel 14.04 is supported so I will show you how to upgrade your desktop to the latest version and now use the new agent as well.
If you followed my previous post to disable Console access.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading vRealize Operations Horizon Adapter to 6.1</title>
      <link>/2015/09/22/upgrading-vrealize-operations-horizon-adapter-to-61/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/09/22/upgrading-vrealize-operations-horizon-adapter-to-61/</guid>
      <description>vRealize Operations 6.1 is now available, I thought I would put a quick guide together as I go through the upgrade process. This guide will show how to upgrade the Horizon Adapter for vROPS.
To upgrade from vRealize Operations Horizon Adapter to the most recent version, follow these steps.
Download the neccessary file(s) needed. In my case I needed the vRealize Operations for Horizon Broker Agent and the vRealize Operations for Horizon Adapter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading vRealize Operations to 6.1</title>
      <link>/2015/09/22/upgrading-vrealize-operations-to-61/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/09/22/upgrading-vrealize-operations-to-61/</guid>
      <description>vRealize Operations 6.1 is now available, I thought I would put a quick guide together as I go through the upgrade process.
To upgrade from vRealize Operations Manager to the most recent version, follow these steps.
Download the PAK file(s) needed based on the type of cluster.
 vApp clusters  The vApp cluster requires the deployment of the OS upgrade and the product upgrade .pak files. For an OS upgrade, the file is: vRealize_Operations_Manager-VA-OS-xxx.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unable to SSH to vSphere 6 VCSA or PSC</title>
      <link>/2015/09/21/unable-to-ssh-to-vsphere-6-vcsa-or-psc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/09/21/unable-to-ssh-to-vsphere-6-vcsa-or-psc/</guid>
      <description>So I am in the midst of setting up a vSphere 6 POC and it has been a bit since I played with it. I came across a problem I thought i would document and share.
While trying to setup my Platform Service Controllers for HA. I was having issues sshing into the appliance. I kept on getting errors, that the packet sizes were too big or just authentication would fail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unable to join PSC to Domain via Webclient</title>
      <link>/2015/09/21/unable-to-join-psc-to-domain-via-webclient/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/09/21/unable-to-join-psc-to-domain-via-webclient/</guid>
      <description>I am actually pretty surprised this bug still exists. I came across this issue with my first deployment of vSphere 6. Now I am circling back around to do a POC and it still exists.
When trying to join a Platform Services Controller to the domain via the vSphere Webclient I get the following error: &amp;ldquo;java.lang.reflect.invocationTargetException&amp;rdquo;
There are currently two workarounds now with 6.0U1 I am aware of.
 The first method is to join to the domain using the CLI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enabling Biometrics in Horizon View 6.2</title>
      <link>/2015/09/16/enabling-biometrics-in-horizon-view-62/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/09/16/enabling-biometrics-in-horizon-view-62/</guid>
      <description>Horizon 6.2 Introduced Biometric Authentication, with initial support for TouchID on IOS devices.
This post will explain how to enable it, as its not really something greatly documented right now. I think they are aware and hopefully in a future update this will be easier.
Here is a link to the current VMware documentation.
NOTE: This feature does require a 3rd party trusted signed certificate to work. From my current testing and speaking with others self-signed certificates will not function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading Horizon View 6.1 to 6.2</title>
      <link>/2015/09/16/upgrading-horizon-view-61-to-62/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/09/16/upgrading-horizon-view-61-to-62/</guid>
      <description>I had the opportunity to upgrade my Horizon View environment from 6.1 to 6.2. As always VMware has made this very easy!
First download the bits from here.
The upgrade documentation can also be found here.
Warning: In my environment I do not have a composer server, if you had one this would be upgraded first The upgrade order is as follows. Composer Server, Connection Servers and then Security Servers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using PowerCLI to Extend VMDK and Windows OS Disk</title>
      <link>/2015/09/15/using-powercli-to-extend-vmdk-and-windows-os-disk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/09/15/using-powercli-to-extend-vmdk-and-windows-os-disk/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to share this handy script i created when you have a need to extend a disk.
This script can be extremely handy as it will take care of extending the VMDK and then going to the OS and then performing the expansion there as well. This has been helpful when needing to extend a large batch of servers (60+).
Syntax: .\ExtendVMDKandGuest VMNAME
You will then be prompted to enter in the Hard Disk #, the size you want to be extended, and then which drive letter that volume belongs to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using PowerCLI to Detach Luns</title>
      <link>/2015/09/14/using-powercli-to-detach-luns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/09/14/using-powercli-to-detach-luns/</guid>
      <description>I thought I would share this script, its been circulating a bit but I feel it is a nice one to have in your toolkit.
Have you ever had to remove a LUN from a cluster and thought &amp;ldquo;Do I really need to detach all the LUN&amp;rsquo;s, before un-mapping from my SAN?&amp;rdquo;
 Unmount Datastore Detach LUN Un-map from SAN Rescan Cluster  Well here is a handy script with output.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vSphere 6.0 Update 1 Released</title>
      <link>/2015/09/10/vsphere-60-update-1-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/09/10/vsphere-60-update-1-released/</guid>
      <description>Today vSphere 6.0 U1 is released. This is normally the update everyone waits for before upgrading their production environments to the latest version. I think the first time in awhile, a lot of people will wait.
You see, VMware has had a bug KB2124669 since ESXi 6.0 that can cause an ESXi host to randomly lose connection, freeze and overall act really terrible. With the release of 6.0U1 it still exists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Horizon View - Block Linux VDI Console Access</title>
      <link>/2015/07/23/horizon-view-block-linux-vdi-console-access/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/07/23/horizon-view-block-linux-vdi-console-access/</guid>
      <description>So I have had some time to play around with the new Linux Horizon View Agent and using Ubuntu as a VDI guest and it works pretty well. However as most of us have seen, when a user is logged onto the guest the screen is shown in the console. In some organizations this may pose a privacy or security risk.
Right now there is no true workaround as that is how the view session is handled, however there is a workaround to disable console access.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTML Based Published Apps with Horizon View 6.1.1</title>
      <link>/2015/06/10/html-based-published-apps-with-horizon-view-6-1-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/06/10/html-based-published-apps-with-horizon-view-6-1-1/</guid>
      <description>So Horizon View 6.1.1 was released recently with added support for published applications to finally be accessible via the HTML client. The process is pretty straightforward, however I came across one hiccup I wanted to share.
I am assuming you have already upgraded your View Composer, Connection and Security Servers and are now focused on getting the agents up to date.
 Install/Update Agents on virtual desktops to 6.1.1 (The HTML Access 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vSphere6 - Unable to use session credentials</title>
      <link>/2015/04/13/vsphere6-unable-to-use-session-credentials/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/04/13/vsphere6-unable-to-use-session-credentials/</guid>
      <description>So one thing I have come across with a few VCSA6 installs was the inability to use login with current credentials via the Web client or vSphere client.
Working with VMware support we were finally able to get it working with a few tweaks and there is a current pending KB that has not been published yet. (KB2113038) I have been told this affects both an embedded deployment (VCSA and PSC together) and external deployment (VCSA and PSC seperate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerCLI - Extend VMDK and Guest OS</title>
      <link>/2015/04/02/powercli-extend-vmdk-and-guest-os/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/04/02/powercli-extend-vmdk-and-guest-os/</guid>
      <description>So as always things change across multiple Window&amp;rsquo;s operating systems and VMware revisions. I had a need to extend the drives on about 50 VMs today and really didn&amp;rsquo;t want to do all that clicking. I remember awhile back it was easy to do this with a Basic Set-Harddisk and use the -ResizeGuestPartition but alas that has been removed from the current functionality. So I took my search to google and found a couple scripts that worked ok, but nothing that was a seamless experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SRM - Unable to uninstall due to UAC</title>
      <link>/2015/02/18/srm-unable-to-uninstall-due-to-uac/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/02/18/srm-unable-to-uninstall-due-to-uac/</guid>
      <description>I was trying to remove SRM 5.1 from our environment and kept getting an error that UAC must be disabled. Even though UAC was set to &amp;ldquo;Never Notify&amp;rdquo; SRM didnt like this.
To fully disable UAC run the following command from an elevated command prompt and then reboot the system.
REG ADD “HKLM\SOFTWARE\Microsoft\Windows\CurrentVersion\Policies\System” /v EnableLUA /t REG_DWORD /d 0 /f  Note: You can also avoid this by doing the uninstall as the builtin local administrator account</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unable to Configure Event Database in vRealize Operations View Broker Agent</title>
      <link>/2015/02/06/unable-to-configure-event-database-in-vrealize-operations-view-broker-agent/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/02/06/unable-to-configure-event-database-in-vrealize-operations-view-broker-agent/</guid>
      <description>I was in the process of getting vRealize for Horizon configured, and as I was going through the broker agent configuration for the life of me I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get the eventdb portion to work. Everytime i entered in the user name and password, I would receive the following error. FAILED (Format of the initialization string does not conform to specification starting at index 88.)
I knew it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a password issue as I was able to logon to SQL Manager with no issue, and the Horizon View EventsDB was working fine, so I went on a google search to try to hunt through logs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerCLI - Troubleshooting Multiple Default Servers</title>
      <link>/2015/01/29/powercli-troubleshooting-multiple-default-servers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/01/29/powercli-troubleshooting-multiple-default-servers/</guid>
      <description>I use a customized version of http://www.virtu-al.net/vcheck-pluginsheaders/vcheck/ by Alan Renouf to connect to multiple servers. However a coworker of mine was trying to run it, and the script would only return data from the 2nd vCenter we were connecting to.
Doing some troubleshooting we noticed their DefaultVIServerMode was set to single. This means that only a single servers connection will occur at once. Changing this setting is very easy, there are 3 scopes, but only one really needs to be set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerCLI - Enable CPU and Memory HotAdd</title>
      <link>/2015/01/14/powercli-enable-cpu-and-memory-hotadd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/01/14/powercli-enable-cpu-and-memory-hotadd/</guid>
      <description>I had a need to enable CPU and Memory hotadd to many virtual machines prior to a template being updated, doing some research there is no easy way, however there are some functions out there to do it. You can copy and paste each function into a powershell window and then run the associated command.
Enable-MemHotAdd $ServerName Disable-MemHotAdd $ServerName Enable-vCPUHotAdd $ServerName Disable-vCPUHotAdd $ServerName  Enable Memory HotAdd Function Enable-MemHotAdd($vm){ $vmview = Get-vm $vm | Get-View $vmConfigSpec = New-Object VMware.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vSphere Data Protection - Insufficient Disk Space for Upgrade</title>
      <link>/2014/09/22/vmware-data-protection-insuffient-disk-space-for-upgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/09/22/vmware-data-protection-insuffient-disk-space-for-upgrade/</guid>
      <description>As I was upgrading my VDP-A environment from 5.5 to 5.8 the upgrade failed due to the following error.
&amp;ldquo;Please make sure you have at least 20GB for repo, 10GB for var, and 1GB for root partition.&amp;rdquo;
Upon further research there seems to be an issue from 5.5.1 and 5.5.5 appliances with the /space partition filling up due to PostGres events. The issue can be resolving by installing the following VDP patch (vdp_patch-5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sysprep runs repeatedly on virtual machines deployed to ESXi 5.1 build 1743533</title>
      <link>/2014/07/08/sysprep-runs-repeatedly-on-virtual-machines-deployed-to-esxi-5-1-build-1743533/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/07/08/sysprep-runs-repeatedly-on-virtual-machines-deployed-to-esxi-5-1-build-1743533/</guid>
      <description>We had a strange issue that any time a VM was snapshotted it then forced a reboot and sysprep. Reviewing the customization logs(C:\windows\temp\vmware-imc\guestcust.log) I noticed the following error..Unable to set customization status in vmx.
Upon further research it seems this is a known issue and is resolved in ESXi 5.1 Express Patch 5 KB2077640 as referenced in this article KB2078352.
However the hotfix only fixes future occurences, you still need to fix all the VMs affected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring ESXi 5.5 Dump Collector</title>
      <link>/2014/06/10/configuring-esxi-5-5-dump-collector/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/06/10/configuring-esxi-5-5-dump-collector/</guid>
      <description>Thank you to everyone who listened to me on the EMEA vBrownbag. Here are copies of documentation and scripts on how to configure ESXi to use the remote dump collector.
Check the ESXi Dump Collector Configuration Example: Foreach ($vmhost in (get-vmhost)){ $esxcli = Get-EsxCli -vmhost $vmhost $esxcli.system.coredump.network.get()}  Setting the ESXi Dump Collector Example: Foreach ($vmhost in (get-vmhost)) { $esxcli = Get-EsxCli -vmhost $vmhost $esxcli.system.coredump.network.set($null, “vmk0″, “IPtoDumpCollector″, “6500″) $esxcli.system.coredump.network.set($true)}  Test Host by Causing PSOD Run the following command via SSH or Direct Shell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring ESXi 5.5 Syslog Collector</title>
      <link>/2014/06/10/configuring-esxi-5-5-syslog-collector/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/06/10/configuring-esxi-5-5-syslog-collector/</guid>
      <description>Thank you to everyone who listened to me on the EMEA vBrownbag. Here are copies of documentation and scripts on how to configure ESXi to use the Syslog collector.
Check the ESXi Syslog Collector Configuration Example: Foreach ($vmhost in (get-vmhost)){ $esxcli = Get-EsxCli -vmhost $vmhost $esxcli.system.syslog.config.get()}  Setting the ESXi Syslog Collector Example: Foreach ($vmhost in (get-vmhost)){ $esxcli = Get-EsxCli -vmhost $vmhost $esxcli.system.syslog.config.set($null, $null, $null, $null,&amp;quot;udp://IPtoSyslogServer:514″) $esxcli.system.syslog.reload()}  Post-Installation Changes If you wish to change the default port or maxsize of the syslog rotation, these can be changed by modifying the vmconfig-syslog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying vCloud Connector 2.6 and Configuring For vCHS (Part 3)</title>
      <link>/2014/06/04/deploying-vcloud-connector-2-6-and-configuring-for-vchs-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/06/04/deploying-vcloud-connector-2-6-and-configuring-for-vchs-part-3/</guid>
      <description>In Part 1 we showed you how to deploy vCloud Connector 2.6, and in Part 2 we showed you how to configure it.
Here in Part 3 we will show you how to migrate a workload from your private cloud to your public cloud.
Lets go back to our vCenter and select our vCloud Connector Plugin
Expand your vCenter and select the folder that contains the VM you wish to copy to vCHS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying vCloud Connector 2.6 and Configuring For vCHS (Part 1)</title>
      <link>/2014/06/03/deploying-vcloud-connector-2-6-and-configuring-for-vchs-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/06/03/deploying-vcloud-connector-2-6-and-configuring-for-vchs-part-1/</guid>
      <description>So luckily i was selected for the June 2014 wave of vCloud Hybrid Service access as a vExpert. I have been looking forwarding to using vCHS since it went GA and am glad to finally have the opportunity to use it hands on.
Once I got access I knew I wanted to copy some of my existing workloads to vCHS instead of having to start from scratch. I begin to look for some good guides on implementing vCloud Connector 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying vCloud Connector 2.6 and Configuring For vCHS (Part 2)</title>
      <link>/2014/06/03/deploying-vcloud-connector-2-6-and-configuring-for-vchs-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/06/03/deploying-vcloud-connector-2-6-and-configuring-for-vchs-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Here is Part 2 a continuation of Deploying vCloud Connector 2.6 and Configuring For vCHS (Part 1) (http://davidstamen.com/2014/06/03/deploying-vcloud-connector-2-6-and-configuring-for-vchs-part-1/) where we will configure vCloud connector to your Private(vCenter) and Public(vCHS) clouds.
Lets start with getting the vCloud Connector Server ready. Just in case you forgot what IP you assigned we can open the appliance and view the management information.
As we can see here the URL to configure the appliace is https://192.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create VMFS Datastore Using PowerCLI</title>
      <link>/2014/05/22/create-vmfs-datastore-using-powercli/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/05/22/create-vmfs-datastore-using-powercli/</guid>
      <description>For upcoming testing there was a need to create 140 datastores on a cluster for testing. Who wants to do that much clicking and typing? Not me! You can use the below PowerCLI commands to get the SCSI ID&amp;rsquo;s, Create the Datastore and then Rescan all hosts in the cluster.
How do i get the CanonicalName for allocated disks? Get-SCSILun -VMhost 192.168.1.103 -LunType Disk | Select CanonicalName,Capacity  How do I create a VMFS datastore for the CanonicalName I identified above?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vSphere 5.x Storage vMotion Does Not Rename Virtual Machine Files.</title>
      <link>/2014/05/21/vsphere-5-x-storage-vmotion-does-not-rename-virtual-machine-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/05/21/vsphere-5-x-storage-vmotion-does-not-rename-virtual-machine-files/</guid>
      <description>After upgrading vCenter this functionality is no longer enabled by default. Please perform the following steps to enable rename of files upon successful Storage vMotion.
 Log into the vSphere Client as an Administrator Click Administration &amp;gt; vCenter Server Settings Click Advanced Settings Add this advanced parameter key: provisioning.relocate.enableRename Set the value to: true Click Add Click OK Restart the VMware VirtualCenter Server service for the changes to take effect  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HA Error: Datastore Heartbeat is less than 2</title>
      <link>/2014/05/08/ha-error-datastore-heartbeat-is-less-than-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/05/08/ha-error-datastore-heartbeat-is-less-than-2/</guid>
      <description>If you are configuring a cluster with less than 2 datastores, you will receive an HA warning &amp;ldquo;The number of heartbeat datastores for host is 1, which is less than required: 2&amp;rdquo; You can add an option to the HA Advanced Options to supress this warning.
 Log in to vCenter Server Right-click the cluster and click Edit Settings Click vSphere HA &amp;gt; Advanced Options Under Option, add an entry for das.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HA Error: Network Redundancy</title>
      <link>/2014/05/08/ha-error-network-redundancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/05/08/ha-error-network-redundancy/</guid>
      <description>When setting up a cluster for testing you may not have 2 nics to use for management. to bypass the warning you can configure HA to not alert you for this issue.
To perform the steps in the c# client.  From the VMware Infrastructure Client, right-click on the cluster and click Edit Settings. Select vSphere HA and click Advanced Options. In the Options column, enter das.ignoreRedundantNetWarning In the Value column, type true Click OK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get NAA.ID for Virtual Machine RDM&#39;s in VMware</title>
      <link>/2014/05/06/get-naa-id-for-virtual-machine-rdms-in-vmware/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/05/06/get-naa-id-for-virtual-machine-rdms-in-vmware/</guid>
      <description>This is a great script to keep handy. If you have multiple RDM&amp;rsquo;s on a VM and need to get the NAA_ID for them the below PowerCLI command will get you that information.
Get-VM VMNAME| Get-HardDisk -DiskType &amp;quot;RawPhysical&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;RawVirtual&amp;quot; | Select Parent,Name,DiskType,ScsiCanonicalName,DeviceName,CapacityGB | fl  If you then need to match the SCSI virtual disk to the Guest OS this is a great article on how to do so.
KB2051606</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enable SSH on vSphere Management Assistant 5.0</title>
      <link>/2014/05/01/enable-ssh-on-vma-5-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/05/01/enable-ssh-on-vma-5-0/</guid>
      <description>While continuing to build out my lab for VCAP-DCA today I had to deploy the vMA (vSphere Management Assistant). Upon deployment i tried to SSH to it and unfortunately was not able to. By default SSH is turned off, perform the steps below to enable it.
 Logon to vMA via a Console Session Run &amp;lsquo;sudo vi /etc/hosts.allow&amp;rsquo; Scroll to the very bottom and type i to insert content into the file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nested ESXi and NFS</title>
      <link>/2014/04/29/nested-esxi-and-nfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/04/29/nested-esxi-and-nfs/</guid>
      <description>I was working today on configuring NFS/Openfiler in my lab and came across an issue that my nested ESXi host&amp;rsquo;s couldn&amp;rsquo;t talk over the VSS (Standard Switch) I created. Upon further research when using nested ESXi you need to enable &amp;ldquo;Promiscuous Mode&amp;rdquo; on the VSS to allow the traffic to pass.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>