<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vrealize Operations on davidstamen.com</title>
    <link>/categories/vrealize-operations/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vrealize Operations on davidstamen.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/vrealize-operations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using PowerCLI to Add vRealize Operations License Key</title>
      <link>/2017/07/27/using-powercli-to-add-vrealize-operations-license-key/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/07/27/using-powercli-to-add-vrealize-operations-license-key/</guid>
      <description>I have been working on doing a vCenter Consolidation Project. This included migrating our systems to a new vRealize Operations Server. This particular one included 73 different vSOM keys, and as you may know there is currently no way to enter in multiple keys at a time. I reached out to Kyle Ruddy and he informed me there is an API to do this, and that started my adventure to get this working.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading vRealize Operations Horizon Adapter to 6.1</title>
      <link>/2015/09/22/upgrading-vrealize-operations-horizon-adapter-to-61/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/09/22/upgrading-vrealize-operations-horizon-adapter-to-61/</guid>
      <description>vRealize Operations 6.1 is now available, I thought I would put a quick guide together as I go through the upgrade process. This guide will show how to upgrade the Horizon Adapter for vROPS.
To upgrade from vRealize Operations Horizon Adapter to the most recent version, follow these steps.
Download the neccessary file(s) needed. In my case I needed the vRealize Operations for Horizon Broker Agent and the vRealize Operations for Horizon Adapter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading vRealize Operations to 6.1</title>
      <link>/2015/09/22/upgrading-vrealize-operations-to-61/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/09/22/upgrading-vrealize-operations-to-61/</guid>
      <description>vRealize Operations 6.1 is now available, I thought I would put a quick guide together as I go through the upgrade process.
To upgrade from vRealize Operations Manager to the most recent version, follow these steps.
Download the PAK file(s) needed based on the type of cluster.
 vApp clusters  The vApp cluster requires the deployment of the OS upgrade and the product upgrade .pak files. For an OS upgrade, the file is: vRealize_Operations_Manager-VA-OS-xxx.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unable to Configure Event Database in vRealize Operations View Broker Agent</title>
      <link>/2015/02/06/unable-to-configure-event-database-in-vrealize-operations-view-broker-agent/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/02/06/unable-to-configure-event-database-in-vrealize-operations-view-broker-agent/</guid>
      <description>I was in the process of getting vRealize for Horizon configured, and as I was going through the broker agent configuration for the life of me I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get the eventdb portion to work. Everytime i entered in the user name and password, I would receive the following error. FAILED (Format of the initialization string does not conform to specification starting at index 88.)
I knew it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a password issue as I was able to logon to SQL Manager with no issue, and the Horizon View EventsDB was working fine, so I went on a google search to try to hunt through logs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>