<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>vCenter Server on davidstamen.com</title>
    <link>/tags/vcenter-server/</link>
    <description>Recent content in vCenter Server on davidstamen.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/vcenter-server/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Considerations for vSphere Component Backup and Restore: Part 2</title>
      <link>/2019/10/23/considerations-for-vsphere-component-backup-and-restore-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/23/considerations-for-vsphere-component-backup-and-restore-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Now that we have covered the considerations to backup each component in your vSphere Environment, it&amp;rsquo;s time to think about the rollback or restore process. In the previous post we discussed how to backup each individual component, in this post we will continue the conversation and discuss considerations to restore or rollback your vSphere Environment components.
Platform Services Controller / vCenter Server When things don&amp;rsquo;t go right with an update, upgrade or configuration change of your Platform Services Controller or vCenter Server you need to understand the proper steps it takes to rollback.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Considerations for vSphere Component Backup and Restore: Part 1</title>
      <link>/2019/10/21/considerations-for-vsphere-component-backup-and-restore-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/21/considerations-for-vsphere-component-backup-and-restore-part-1/</guid>
      <description>You spend time planning and implementing updates, upgrades and configuration changes to vSphere Environments. Rollback or recovery is usually the last thing on the mind. Did you know there are multiple ways to successfully backup each component in a vSphere Environment? There are also many ways to recover those same components.
In this series we will talk about considerations to backup and restore or rollback your vSphere environment if we have a need to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Server 2008 is Going EOL - What about my vCenter Server?</title>
      <link>/2019/08/12/windows-server-2008-is-going-eol-what-about-my-vcenter-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/08/12/windows-server-2008-is-going-eol-what-about-my-vcenter-server/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Windows Server 2008 and 2008 R2 will be end-of-life on January 14th, 2020. This impacts quite a few folks who may have deployed their vCenter Server for Windows on these Operating Systems. I have been asked quite often recently, &amp;ldquo;What are my options?&amp;rdquo; Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in and find out what it takes to move to a supported OS!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vCenter Server Converge Tool - What About My Certificates</title>
      <link>/2019/06/07/vcenter-server-converge-tool-what-about-my-certificates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/06/07/vcenter-server-converge-tool-what-about-my-certificates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As more customers get ready to run the vCenter Server Converge Tool in their environments, a common question that has been asked is &amp;ldquo;What Happens to my Certificates?&amp;rdquo; Well that is a good question so lets find out!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vCenter Server Appliance CLI - JSON Creator</title>
      <link>/2019/04/24/vcenter-server-appliance-cli-json-creator/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/04/24/vcenter-server-appliance-cli-json-creator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am proud to announce that my first VMware Clarity Project the VCSA JSON Creator is now live! This has been something I have wanted to do for some time, and am glad to finally have the first version available for feedback. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in and take a look.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vCenter Server Converge Tool - How do I Converge an Environment Using the UI</title>
      <link>/2019/04/11/vcenter-server-converge-tool-how-do-i-converge-an-environment-using-the-ui/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/04/11/vcenter-server-converge-tool-how-do-i-converge-an-environment-using-the-ui/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;vSphere 6.7 Update 2 is now available! Inside this update include enhancements to the vCenter Server Converge Tool. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in and take a look at whats new and see how to converge a deployment using the new UI.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patching the vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) using the REST API - Part 2 (PowerCLI Module)</title>
      <link>/2019/01/31/patching-the-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-using-the-rest-api-part-2-powershell-module/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/31/patching-the-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-using-the-rest-api-part-2-powershell-module/</guid>
      <description>Previously I covered how to use the VCSA Installer to do a scripted upgrade and then I covered Patching the vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) using the REST API - Part 1 (Postman Collection) However, after learning recently how to call API&amp;rsquo;s from Powershell I thought to myself, why not write a Powershell Module for this?
Introduction Using tools such as Postman can make it utilizing API&amp;rsquo;s a bit easier, but you still need to be familiar with a separate tool or UI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patching the vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) using the REST API - Part 1 (Postman Collection)</title>
      <link>/2018/12/20/patching-the-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-using-the-rest-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/12/20/patching-the-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-using-the-rest-api/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am a huge fan of Automating the vSphere Lifecycle process. The next step I wanted to cover was patching the vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) using the REST API.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading Platform Services Controller and vCenter Server via the CLI Installer</title>
      <link>/2018/10/05/upgrading-platform-services-controller-and-vcenter-server-via-the-cli-installer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 09:08:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/05/upgrading-platform-services-controller-and-vcenter-server-via-the-cli-installer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first topic we will cover in our Automating your vSphere Upgrade series is updating our core infrastructure. Upgrading Platform Services Controller(PSC)  and vCenter Server via the CLI installer. In our workshops one of the common things I hear is that most folks aren&amp;rsquo;t using the CLI based tools that have been included in the installer. I am a huge fan of these as they make migrations and upgrades seamless&amp;ndash;especially when having to perform the task if you have multiple PSC&amp;rsquo;s and vCenter Servers. Using the CLI tools don’t have to be intimidating, as we go through this blog we will cover some how-to&amp;rsquo;s and benefits of using the CLI based approach.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patching your vCenter Server Appliance from 6.7 to 6.7a</title>
      <link>/2018/05/23/patching-your-vcenter-server-appliance-from-6.7-to-6.7a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 12:45:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/23/patching-your-vcenter-server-appliance-from-6.7-to-6.7a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On May 22nd we released the first update to our vCenter Server 6.7 version, 6.7a. I will let you know how you can patch your 6.7 GA vCenter Server to 6.7a.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading to VMware vSphere 6.7</title>
      <link>/2018/04/17/upgrading-to-vmware-vsphere-6.7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 08:32:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/17/upgrading-to-vmware-vsphere-6.7/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s finally out! vSphere 6.7 is the next major release of VMware&amp;rsquo;s virtualization software. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using 6.7 through the vSphere Beta Program and testing even newer features in my current role. I am here to talk to you about planning your vSphere upgrade and some planning and considerations you should have when going to the latest release.
The first, thing I would like to mention is there is no supported migration from vSphere 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reconfigure HA - The object &#39;vim.Datastore:datastore-XXXX&#39; has already been deleted or has not been completely created</title>
      <link>/2018/01/19/reconfigure-ha-the-object-vim.datastoredatastore-xxxx-has-already-been-deleted-or-has-not-been-completely-created/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 10:27:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/19/reconfigure-ha-the-object-vim.datastoredatastore-xxxx-has-already-been-deleted-or-has-not-been-completely-created/</guid>
      <description>Another lovely Friday starting off with strange issues, when taking a host out of standard maintenance we noticed that HA would not reconfigure, and kept saying The object &amp;lsquo;vim.Datastore:datastore-1131&amp;rsquo; has already been deleted or has not been completely created. This was strange because no other hosts had this issue.
![](/uploads/screenshot-2018-01-19 10-23-44.png)
I proceeded to follow standard troubleshooting steps, reconfigure HA&amp;hellip;same issue&amp;hellip;.disable HA for entire cluster and re-enable&amp;hellip;..same issue&amp;hellip;whoops thats not good!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vCenter 6.5U1 Update Issues with VCHA Advanced Deployment</title>
      <link>/2017/08/02/vcenter-6.5u1-update-issues-with-vcha-advanced-deployment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 16:08:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/08/02/vcenter-6.5u1-update-issues-with-vcha-advanced-deployment/</guid>
      <description>vSphere 6.5U1 was released on July 27th. This is an incremental update a lot of people wait for before upgrading from a previous version. I have been lucky to have been running on vSphere 6.5 for quite some time and have been enjoying it very much.
Obviously we never upgrade production first, if we can help it. I decided to attempt an upgrade on one of our QA vCenters that was deployed using the VCHA Advanced workflow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using PowerCLI to Set vCenter Permissions on Datacenter</title>
      <link>/2017/04/17/using-powercli-to-set-vcenter-permissions-on-datacenter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/04/17/using-powercli-to-set-vcenter-permissions-on-datacenter/</guid>
      <description>I have been working on doing a vCenter Consolidation Project. This has meant recreating multiple permissions groups. I couldnt find an easy way to apply permissions at a datacenter so I updated this script to be used.
Pre-Requsites   VMware PowerCLI  Link to Script   Set-vCenterPermissions.ps1  permissions.csv  Preparing to Execute the Script The script is pretty straight forward, just need to update columns in the CSV such as Datacenter, Group and Role.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vSphere 6.5 - Updating Appliance configured with vCenter HA</title>
      <link>/2017/02/03/vsphere-65-updating-appliance-configured-with-vcenter-ha/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/02/03/vsphere-65-updating-appliance-configured-with-vcenter-ha/</guid>
      <description>Warning: A few others and myself have noticed that when updating a VCHA Cluster to 6.5U1 it resets the hostname to localhost.localdomain stopping vCenter Web Client from Loading. It seems to be isolated to Advanced Deployments and not Basic. I would recommend destroying your VCHA Cluster, updating, then redeploying in this scenario. Warning2: It also seems that if you try to redeploy VCHA Advanced after an upgrade, it still resets the hostname, I have a case opened and will update here as neccessary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using PowerCLI to Build Out vCenter</title>
      <link>/2015/10/08/using-powercli-to-build-out-vcenter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/10/08/using-powercli-to-build-out-vcenter/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to share this handy script i created when you have a need to build out a new vCenter.
This script can be extremely handy as it will take care of creating the datacenter, cluster, adding hosts, creating datastores and then applying the appropriate host profile. It is all done via CSV files so it is extremely customizable.
Files to modify to customize your configuration  createdatacenter.csv - Contains the name of the datacenter to create.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>