<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jekyll on davidstamen.com</title>
    <link>/tags/jekyll/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jekyll on davidstamen.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/jekyll/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying and Hosting Jekyll on Ravello Systems</title>
      <link>/2015/09/08/deploying-and-hosting-jekyll-on-ravello-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/09/08/deploying-and-hosting-jekyll-on-ravello-systems/</guid>
      <description>Did you know you could get host your own blog on Ravello Systems?
Its actually quite easy and even easier with Jekyll. Jekyll is a great static content platform perfect for hosting your blog. It is all based on html/css/markdown and requires absolutely no database.
Please use my previous blog on how to get it deployed.
Disclaimer: This is in no way supported or recommended by Ravello Systems, running this 24x7 even with 1CPU will consume most of your free trial/vExpert hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Deploy a Jekyll Blog</title>
      <link>/2015/09/08/how-to-deploy-a-jekyll-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/09/08/how-to-deploy-a-jekyll-blog/</guid>
      <description>So after getting my blog up and running I figured I would do a quick how-to, on how to get a blog up and running. Its actually something you can do in less than 15 minutes.
~ $ gem install jekyll ~ $ jekyll new myblog ~ $ cd myblog ~/myblog $ jekyll serve # = Now browse to http://localhost:4000 and you will see the blog running! Easy Enough? Now how do you create a blog post?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Jekyll!</title>
      <link>/2015/09/04/updated-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/09/04/updated-platform/</guid>
      <description>New Blog Platform! I have had a bit of issues with performance on my blog recently and looking on how to not overpay for hosting services. A good friend of mine suggested using Jekyll and GitHub Pages, so I took the challenge. Within a day I was able to get my blog posts exported from Wordpress and published on a new platform and it was quite simple! Be on the lookout for some upcoming posts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>