<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pure1 on davidstamen</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/tags/pure1/</link><description>Recent content in Pure1 on davidstamen</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2008–2018, Steve Francia and the Hugo Authors; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidstamen.com/tags/pure1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What's New in Pure1 VM Analytics and OVA Collector 3.0</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/whats-new-vm-analytics-collector-3-0/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/whats-new-vm-analytics-collector-3-0/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;On November 16, 2020 the latest version of the Pure1 VM Analytics OVA Collector (3.0) was released and with it comes some new Pure1 features! Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at how the collector has changed, and what new features we now have within Pure1 VM Analytics.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Using Pure1 Meta for Intelligent Datastore Selection and VM Provisioning</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/11/11/using-pure1-meta-for-intelligent-datastore-selection-and-vm-provisioning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/11/11/using-pure1-meta-for-intelligent-datastore-selection-and-vm-provisioning/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When it comes to monitoring your Pure Storage environment Pure1 is a great place for that. It is also a great place to use your analytic&amp;rsquo;s data to your advantage and use it for intelligent VMware provisioning! In this blog post I will cover how to use this data to your advantage to make sure you can easily deploy VM&amp;rsquo;s to the most optimal array and datastore.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Using Terraform to Deploy the Pure1 VM Analytics Collector</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/06/30/using-terraform-to-deploy-the-pure1-vm-analytics-collector/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 07:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/06/30/using-terraform-to-deploy-the-pure1-vm-analytics-collector/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Pure1 VM Analytics is a great tool to have in your environment. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to even have a Pure Storage array, but it makes it even better! Back in 2019 the collector was converted to an OVA format and has been much simpler to deploy. You can deploy it through the UI or even Powershell. With the latest update to the Terraform vSphere provider we can now deploy OVA&amp;rsquo;s, so lets jump in to see how we can deploy the VM Analytics collector!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Configuring vRealize Orchestrator to use Pure1 Integration</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/06/05/configuring-vrealize-orchestrator-to-use-pure1-integration/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/06/05/configuring-vrealize-orchestrator-to-use-pure1-integration/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The more I play with our integrations the more I am impressed. My latest project within vRealize Orchestrator had me utilizing our Pure1 integration. This post will cover how to generate the needed pieces to configure the Pure1 Integration within vRO.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Configuring and Using the Pure Storage vSphere Plugin with Pure1 Authentication</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/03/25/configuring-and-using-the-pure-storage-vsphere-plugin-with-pure1-authentication/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/03/25/configuring-and-using-the-pure-storage-vsphere-plugin-with-pure1-authentication/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Beginning with version 4.2.0 the Pure Storage vSphere Client Plugin had a whole slew of new features added, one of those features was the ability to integrate authentication with Pure1 allowing fleet registration of all your Pure Storage Arrays among other things. This does require a slight change on how you would normally register your arrays in the plugin, so lets take a look at how we can accomplish this!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>