<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Personal on davidstamen</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/categories/personal/</link><description>Recent content in Personal on davidstamen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2008–2018, Steve Francia and the Hugo Authors; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidstamen.com/categories/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Back to Work, I'm Going to</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/02/12/back-to-work-im-going-to/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/02/12/back-to-work-im-going-to/</guid><description>When the unfortunate reduction in force (RIF) struck in January at VMware, I was in disbelief and didn&amp;rsquo;t even know where to start. Over the past two years I had the amazing opportunity to not only present to customers and partners in places I never imagined, but the ability to be an internal subject matter expert and create some amazing content. VMware is an amazing place to work and the relationships I&amp;rsquo;ve made and my impact to the products are beyond things I thought I could ever accomplish.</description></item><item><title>To Infinity and Beyond</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2018/02/06/to-infinity-and-beyond/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 10:34:32 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2018/02/06/to-infinity-and-beyond/</guid><description>Life can always surprise you. For the past few years I have been chasing the dream like most to work for the “mothership” and recently the calling came.
This month, I will be joining the CPBU at VMware as a Technical Marketing Engineer focused on vSphere upgrades. I will be working alongside Adam Eckerle, Emad Younis, Kyle Ruddy, Mike Foley, Brian Graf, Nigel Hickey and more!
Nigel has it perfect when he titled his announcement “Oh the places you’ll go”.</description></item><item><title>My New Desk by StandDesk</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2017/08/24/my-new-desk-by-standdesk/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 16:33:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2017/08/24/my-new-desk-by-standdesk/</guid><description>I have been looking for a new desk for awhile. Working from home I do not get to go into an office, or walk around to meet up with coworkers. I found myself sitting for way too long which hasn&amp;rsquo;t been best for the low back and leg pains I experience.
I heard from a friend that getting a standing desk may be something that would be good. Standing desks come in all shapes and sizes but I knew from the start that I wanted a dedicated standing desk and just not a riser (one that sits on an existing desk).</description></item></channel></rss>