<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Amazon Web Services on davidstamen</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/tags/amazon-web-services/</link><description>Recent content in Amazon Web Services on davidstamen</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2008–2018, Steve Francia and the Hugo Authors; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidstamen.com/tags/amazon-web-services/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Guide to Using iPXE + Pure Cloud Block Store for Stateless EC2 Instances - Part 3</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2025/08/11/a-guide-to-using-ipxe--pure-cloud-block-store-for-stateless-ec2-instances-part-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2025/08/11/a-guide-to-using-ipxe--pure-cloud-block-store-for-stateless-ec2-instances-part-3/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome back to Part 3 of the Using iPXE + Pure Cloud Block Store (CBS) for Stateless EC2. In the first part of the series we covered getting all the details ready, Part 2 did a deeper into the AWS and Pure Storage ecosystem and now part 3 will include some advanced day 2 automation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Guide to Using iPXE + Pure Cloud Block Store for Stateless EC2 Instances - Part 2</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2025/08/08/a-guide-to-using-ipxe--pure-cloud-block-store-for-stateless-ec2-instances-part-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2025/08/08/a-guide-to-using-ipxe--pure-cloud-block-store-for-stateless-ec2-instances-part-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome back to Part 2 of the Using iPXE + Pure Cloud Block Store (CBS) for Stateless EC2. In the first part of the series we covered getting all the details ready, Part 2 will dive deeper into the AWS and Pure Storage ecosystem to get an EC2 instance deployed running on an iSCSI SAN booted volume.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Guide to Using iPXE + Pure Cloud Block Store for Stateless EC2 Instances - Part 1</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2025/08/07/a-guide-to-using-ipxe--pure-cloud-block-store-for-stateless-ec2-instances-part-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2025/08/07/a-guide-to-using-ipxe--pure-cloud-block-store-for-stateless-ec2-instances-part-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>Are you searching for a more modern approach to deploying and managing your Amazon EC2 fleet? While the traditional EC2 boot process is dependable, it relies on local EBS storage. In this guide, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to leverage Pure Cloud Block Store to overcome this limitation by using an iPXE-based AMI. This method enables you to bootstrap EC2 instances over iSCSI, allowing for fully stateless deployments.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using CloudFormation to Manage EC2 in AWS</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2023/03/30/using-cloudformation-to-manage-ec2-in-aws/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2023/03/30/using-cloudformation-to-manage-ec2-in-aws/</guid><description>&lt;p>An update to a topic I previously covered! How can we automate management of virtual machines in AWS? Cloud Formation (CFT) is another way that can accomplish it. This blog will identify how you can create, update and delete a CFT stack to be able to manage your EC2 infrastructure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using the AWS CLI to Collect Amazon S3 Bucket Object Information</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2023/02/14/using-the-aws-cli-to-collect-amazon-s3-bucket-object-information/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2023/02/14/using-the-aws-cli-to-collect-amazon-s3-bucket-object-information/</guid><description>&lt;p>Data collection is the theme of the month! This next ask was to easily identify S3 bucket objects, based on name, class of storage and time created.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using the AWS CLI to Collect Amazon Elastic Block Store (EBS) Information</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2023/02/10/using-the-aws-cli-to-collect-amazon-elastic-block-store-ebs-information/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2023/02/10/using-the-aws-cli-to-collect-amazon-elastic-block-store-ebs-information/</guid><description>&lt;p>Most of my recent blogs have been focused on not just how to &amp;ldquo;do&amp;rdquo; something, but provide some information on how things work. This specific blog will cover how we can use the AWS CLI to gather information and format it in a way that is useful. This collection will provide not only information about an EBS volume, but also the instance that is attached, identify the boot volumes and even provide the instance type.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Understanding Block Storage in Amazon Web Services</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2022/05/02/understanding-block-storage-in-amazon-web-services/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2022/05/02/understanding-block-storage-in-amazon-web-services/</guid><description>&lt;p>When running workloads in the Public Cloud such as Amazon Web Services, you have a bunch of options when it comes to block storage. How do you know which one to pick? There are alot of choices&amp;ndash;tradeoffs, features and sprawl can also occur. In this blog I will cover the different types of disks available to help educate you on some of the purposes and limitations of each. I previously covered what this looks like in Microsoft Azure and figured now would be a good time to cover the differences in AWS.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pure Cloud Block Store on AWS - Quick Launch</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2021/07/26/pure-cloud-block-store-on-aws-quick-launch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2021/07/26/pure-cloud-block-store-on-aws-quick-launch/</guid><description>&lt;p>In previous posts I have covered use cases on how to utilize Pure Cloud Block Store (CBS), but if we look back I haven&amp;rsquo;t explained how it can be deployed. This blog will cover how to quickly launch CBS with the pre-requisites in AWS.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using the Pure Storage Cloud Block Store Terraform Provider for AWS</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2021/02/10/using-the-pure-storage-cloud-block-store-terraform-provider-for-aws/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2021/02/10/using-the-pure-storage-cloud-block-store-terraform-provider-for-aws/</guid><description>&lt;p>Im excited to announce the first release of the Pure Storage Cloud Block Store (CBS) Terraform Provider. The first release introduces support for Cloud Block Store on AWS. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in and take a look at how to utilize the new provider!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deploying a Linux EC2 Instance with Hashicorp Terraform and Vault to AWS and Connect to Pure Cloud Block Store</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-linux-ec2-using-terraform-vault/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-linux-ec2-using-terraform-vault/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another update to my &amp;ldquo;Terraforming AWS&amp;rdquo; series is the ability to deploy a Linux based Instance and connect to an existing data volume sitting on the Pure Cloud Block Store. This post will cover how to setup your environment and deploy and bootstrap your linux instance to connect via ISCSI.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deploying a EC2 Instance with PowerShell to AWS</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-ec2-using-powershell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-ec2-using-powershell/</guid><description>&lt;p>Previously, I covered how to Deploy and Bootstrap an EC2 Instance in AWS using Terraform. Not everyone may use Terraform, but quite a few people are using PowerShell today. Lets take a Look at how we can use AWSPowerShell to deploy an EC2 instance in AWS.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deploying a Windows EC2 Instance with Hashicorp Terraform and Vault to AWS</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-ec2-using-terraform-vault/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-ec2-using-terraform-vault/</guid><description>&lt;p>As part of demonstrating our products to customers, I tend to reprovision EC2 instances to show how easy it is to mount data in AWS to Cloud Block Store. After doing this manually a little too often, I figured why not automate it? Check out this blog on how I use Terraform to deploy a EC2 instance and configure it for in-guest iSCSI.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>