<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Amazon Web Services on davidstamen</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/tags/amazon-web-services/</link><description>Recent content in Amazon Web Services on davidstamen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2008–2018, Steve Francia and the Hugo Authors; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidstamen.com/tags/amazon-web-services/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pure Cloud Block Store on AWS - Quick Launch</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2021/07/26/pure-cloud-block-store-on-aws-quick-launch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2021/07/26/pure-cloud-block-store-on-aws-quick-launch/</guid><description>&lt;p>In previous posts I have covered use cases on how to utilize Pure Cloud Block Store (CBS), but if we look back I haven&amp;rsquo;t explained how it can be deployed. This blog will cover how to quickly launch CBS with the pre-requisites in AWS.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using the Pure Storage Cloud Block Store Terraform Provider for AWS</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2021/02/10/using-the-pure-storage-cloud-block-store-terraform-provider-for-aws/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2021/02/10/using-the-pure-storage-cloud-block-store-terraform-provider-for-aws/</guid><description>&lt;p>Im excited to announce the first release of the Pure Storage Cloud Block Store (CBS) Terraform Provider. The first release introduces support for Cloud Block Store on AWS. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in and take a look at how to utilize the new provider!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deploying a Linux EC2 Instance with Hashicorp Terraform and Vault to AWS and Connect to Pure Cloud Block Store</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-linux-ec2-using-terraform-vault/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-linux-ec2-using-terraform-vault/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another update to my &amp;ldquo;Terraforming AWS&amp;rdquo; series is the ability to deploy a Linux based Instance and connect to an existing data volume sitting on the Pure Cloud Block Store. This post will cover how to setup your environment and deploy and bootstrap your linux instance to connect via ISCSI.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deploying a EC2 Instance with PowerShell to AWS</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-ec2-using-powershell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-ec2-using-powershell/</guid><description>&lt;p>Previously, I covered how to Deploy and Bootstrap an EC2 Instance in AWS using Terraform. Not everyone may use Terraform, but quite a few people are using PowerShell today. Lets take a Look at how we can use AWSPowerShell to deploy an EC2 instance in AWS.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deploying a Windows EC2 Instance with Hashicorp Terraform and Vault to AWS</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-ec2-using-terraform-vault/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-ec2-using-terraform-vault/</guid><description>&lt;p>As part of demonstrating our products to customers, I tend to reprovision EC2 instances to show how easy it is to mount data in AWS to Cloud Block Store. After doing this manually a little too often, I figured why not automate it? Check out this blog on how I use Terraform to deploy a EC2 instance and configure it for in-guest iSCSI.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>