<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>AVI Networks on davidstamen</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/tags/avi-networks/</link><description>Recent content in AVI Networks on davidstamen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2008–2018, Steve Francia and the Hugo Authors; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidstamen.com/tags/avi-networks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Modify Resources of the NSX Advanced Load Balancer Service Engine for vSphere with Tanzu</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2021/03/12/modify-resources-of-the-nsx-advanced-load-balancer-service-engine-for-vsphere-with-tanzu/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2021/03/12/modify-resources-of-the-nsx-advanced-load-balancer-service-engine-for-vsphere-with-tanzu/</guid><description>&lt;p>In a previous role I have used Avi Networks and I love their load balancing solution. If you do not pay attention to the default settings, the Service Engines that handle load balancing deploy at 1 cpu and 2 gb of ram. With this blog I will cover how to change that if you have already deployed the NSX ALB and vSphere with Tanzu or any other Virtual Services.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deploy vSphere with Tanzu using vSphere Networking with the NSX Advanced Load Balancer</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2021/03/11/deploy-vsphere-with-tanzu-using-vsphere-networking-with-the-nsx-advanced-load-balancer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2021/03/11/deploy-vsphere-with-tanzu-using-vsphere-networking-with-the-nsx-advanced-load-balancer/</guid><description>&lt;p>In my previous post we covered how to deploy the NSX Advanced Load Balancer for use with vSphere with Tanzu. This post will go over the vSphere with Tanzu configuration to use that NSX Advanced Load Balancer&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deploy and Configure the NSX Advanced Load Balancer for vSphere with Tanzu</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2021/03/10/deploy-and-configure-the-nsx-advanced-load-balancer-for-vsphere-with-tanzu/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2021/03/10/deploy-and-configure-the-nsx-advanced-load-balancer-for-vsphere-with-tanzu/</guid><description>&lt;p>VMware has just released vSphere 7.0 Update 2! With this release NSX Advanced Load Balancer also known as AVI Networks is now a supported load-balancer alongside HA Proxy for vSphere Network deployments. This blog will cover how to deploy and configure the load balancer for use with vSphere with Tanzu.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>