<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cloud Block Store on davidstamen</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/tags/cloud-block-store/</link><description>Recent content in Cloud Block Store on davidstamen</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2008–2018, Steve Francia and the Hugo Authors; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidstamen.com/tags/cloud-block-store/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Guide to Using iPXE + Pure Cloud Block Store for Stateless EC2 Instances - Part 3</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2025/08/11/a-guide-to-using-ipxe--pure-cloud-block-store-for-stateless-ec2-instances-part-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2025/08/11/a-guide-to-using-ipxe--pure-cloud-block-store-for-stateless-ec2-instances-part-3/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome back to Part 3 of the Using iPXE + Pure Cloud Block Store (CBS) for Stateless EC2. In the first part of the series we covered getting all the details ready, Part 2 did a deeper into the AWS and Pure Storage ecosystem and now part 3 will include some advanced day 2 automation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Guide to Using iPXE + Pure Cloud Block Store for Stateless EC2 Instances - Part 2</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2025/08/08/a-guide-to-using-ipxe--pure-cloud-block-store-for-stateless-ec2-instances-part-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2025/08/08/a-guide-to-using-ipxe--pure-cloud-block-store-for-stateless-ec2-instances-part-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome back to Part 2 of the Using iPXE + Pure Cloud Block Store (CBS) for Stateless EC2. In the first part of the series we covered getting all the details ready, Part 2 will dive deeper into the AWS and Pure Storage ecosystem to get an EC2 instance deployed running on an iSCSI SAN booted volume.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Guide to Using iPXE + Pure Cloud Block Store for Stateless EC2 Instances - Part 1</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2025/08/07/a-guide-to-using-ipxe--pure-cloud-block-store-for-stateless-ec2-instances-part-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2025/08/07/a-guide-to-using-ipxe--pure-cloud-block-store-for-stateless-ec2-instances-part-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>Are you searching for a more modern approach to deploying and managing your Amazon EC2 fleet? While the traditional EC2 boot process is dependable, it relies on local EBS storage. In this guide, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to leverage Pure Cloud Block Store to overcome this limitation by using an iPXE-based AMI. This method enables you to bootstrap EC2 instances over iSCSI, allowing for fully stateless deployments.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using Bicep to Deploy a Microsoft SQL on Azure VM with Cloud Block Store Volumes</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2023/05/17/using-bicep-to-deploy-a-microsoft-sql-on-azure-vm-with-cloud-block-store-volumes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2023/05/17/using-bicep-to-deploy-a-microsoft-sql-on-azure-vm-with-cloud-block-store-volumes/</guid><description>&lt;p>This blog will showcase how to deploy an Azure VM that has a configured Microsoft SQL Instance that is connected to a Cloud Block Store (CBS) volume. I have previously showcased VM &amp;amp; CBS deployments with both Powershell and Terraform, but its time to bring it to a new language!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pure Cloud Block Store on AWS - Quick Launch</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2021/07/26/pure-cloud-block-store-on-aws-quick-launch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2021/07/26/pure-cloud-block-store-on-aws-quick-launch/</guid><description>&lt;p>In previous posts I have covered use cases on how to utilize Pure Cloud Block Store (CBS), but if we look back I haven&amp;rsquo;t explained how it can be deployed. This blog will cover how to quickly launch CBS with the pre-requisites in AWS.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pure Cloud Block Store on Azure - Quick Launch</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2021/07/21/pure-cloud-block-store-on-azure-quick-launch/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2021/07/21/pure-cloud-block-store-on-azure-quick-launch/</guid><description>&lt;p>In previous posts I have covered use cases on how to utilize Pure Cloud Block Store (CBS), but if we look back I haven&amp;rsquo;t explained how it can be deployed. This blog will cover how to quickly launch the pre-requisites and get your Pure Cloud Block Store deployed in Azure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using the Pure Storage Cloud Block Store Terraform Provider for Azure</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2021/03/09/using-the-pure-storage-cloud-block-store-terraform-provider-for-azure/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2021/03/09/using-the-pure-storage-cloud-block-store-terraform-provider-for-azure/</guid><description>&lt;p>Im excited to announce the second release of the Pure Storage Cloud Block Store (CBS) Terraform Provider. This release includes support for Cloud Block Store on Azure! Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in and take a look.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cloud Block Store Use Cases for Microsoft Azure - Terraform Edition</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/azure-cbs-terraform-usecases/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/azure-cbs-terraform-usecases/</guid><description>&lt;p>Previously I explained how to use Terraform to Deploy an Azure VM. Now that Cloud Block Store iS GA in Azure, I can cover how to use Automation for Test/Dev, Disaster Recovery and Migration use cases to move workloads from on-premises to Microsoft Azure!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using the Pure Storage Cloud Block Store Terraform Provider for AWS</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2021/02/10/using-the-pure-storage-cloud-block-store-terraform-provider-for-aws/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2021/02/10/using-the-pure-storage-cloud-block-store-terraform-provider-for-aws/</guid><description>&lt;p>Im excited to announce the first release of the Pure Storage Cloud Block Store (CBS) Terraform Provider. The first release introduces support for Cloud Block Store on AWS. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in and take a look at how to utilize the new provider!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deploying a Linux EC2 Instance with Hashicorp Terraform and Vault to AWS and Connect to Pure Cloud Block Store</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-linux-ec2-using-terraform-vault/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-linux-ec2-using-terraform-vault/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another update to my &amp;ldquo;Terraforming AWS&amp;rdquo; series is the ability to deploy a Linux based Instance and connect to an existing data volume sitting on the Pure Cloud Block Store. This post will cover how to setup your environment and deploy and bootstrap your linux instance to connect via ISCSI.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deploying a EC2 Instance with PowerShell to AWS</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-ec2-using-powershell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-ec2-using-powershell/</guid><description>&lt;p>Previously, I covered how to Deploy and Bootstrap an EC2 Instance in AWS using Terraform. Not everyone may use Terraform, but quite a few people are using PowerShell today. Lets take a Look at how we can use AWSPowerShell to deploy an EC2 instance in AWS.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deploying a Windows Azure VM with Hashicorp Terraform to Microsoft Azure</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-avm-using-terraform/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-avm-using-terraform/</guid><description>&lt;p>As a followup to my previous post on Automating EC2 deployments, I figured why not show how this can also be done with Microsoft Azure? Check out how to launch an Azure VM instance and run some scripts to customize your installation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deploying a Windows EC2 Instance with Hashicorp Terraform and Vault to AWS</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-ec2-using-terraform-vault/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-ec2-using-terraform-vault/</guid><description>&lt;p>As part of demonstrating our products to customers, I tend to reprovision EC2 instances to show how easy it is to mount data in AWS to Cloud Block Store. After doing this manually a little too often, I figured why not automate it? Check out this blog on how I use Terraform to deploy a EC2 instance and configure it for in-guest iSCSI.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Running vVols in VMware Cloud on AWS (VMC) on Pure Storage Cloud Block Store (CBS) on AWS</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/running-vvol-on-vmc-on-cbs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/running-vvol-on-vmc-on-cbs/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another post of a cool project this week. With the tools we have available during our hackathon it was asked if we could run vVols in VMware Cloud on AWS. Because of the locked down nature of VMC we could not run vVols directly on that cluster, but I did find a way that we could. Dive into this blog post to see how vVols run on CBS.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>