<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cloud Block Store on davidstamen</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/tags/cloud-block-store/</link><description>Recent content in Cloud Block Store on davidstamen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2008–2018, Steve Francia and the Hugo Authors; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidstamen.com/tags/cloud-block-store/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deploying a Windows Azure VM with Hashicorp Terraform to Microsoft Azure</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-avm-using-terraform/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-avm-using-terraform/</guid><description>&lt;p>As a followup to my previous post on Automating EC2 deployments, I figured why not show how this can also be done with Microsoft Azure? Check out how to launch an Azure VM instance and run some scripts to customize your installation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deploying a Windows EC2 Instance with Hashicorp Terraform and Vault to AWS</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-ec2-using-terraform-vault/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-ec2-using-terraform-vault/</guid><description>&lt;p>As part of demonstrating our products to customers, I tend to reprovision EC2 instances to show how easy it is to mount data in AWS to Cloud Block Store. After doing this manually a little too often, I figured why not automate it? Check out this blog on how I use Terraform to deploy a EC2 instance and configure it for in-guest iSCSI.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Running vVols in VMware Cloud on AWS (VMC) on Pure Storage Cloud Block Store (CBS) on AWS</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/running-vvol-on-vmc-on-cbs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/running-vvol-on-vmc-on-cbs/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another post of a cool project this week. With the tools we have available during our hackathon it was asked if we could run vVols in VMware Cloud on AWS. Because of the locked down nature of VMC we could not run vVols directly on that cluster, but I did find a way that we could. Dive into this blog post to see how vVols run on CBS.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>