<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Webclient on davidstamen</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/tags/webclient/</link><description>Recent content in Webclient on davidstamen</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2008–2018, Steve Francia and the Hugo Authors; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidstamen.com/tags/webclient/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Functional Branding of vSphere Web Client Logon Page</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2017/01/19/functional-branding-of-vsphere-web-client-logon-page/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2017/01/19/functional-branding-of-vsphere-web-client-logon-page/</guid><description>I had a use case I wanted to investigate in regards to the new VCHA that is part of VMware vCenter Server 6.5. One thing I noticed, is when you have VCHA configured, there is no way to know which node of the HA cluster you are connecting to without being logged on.
As people have noted before William Lam&amp;rsquo;s - How to Customize Webclient Login UI
I figured since I am using the embedded SSO, I could update the login page to show any information for that particular node.</description></item><item><title>Unable to join PSC to Domain via Webclient</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2015/09/21/unable-to-join-psc-to-domain-via-webclient/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2015/09/21/unable-to-join-psc-to-domain-via-webclient/</guid><description>I am actually pretty surprised this bug still exists. I came across this issue with my first deployment of vSphere 6. Now I am circling back around to do a POC and it still exists.
When trying to join a Platform Services Controller to the domain via the vSphere Webclient I get the following error: &amp;ldquo;java.lang.reflect.invocationTargetException&amp;rdquo;
There are currently two workarounds now with 6.0U1 I am aware of.
The first method is to join to the domain using the CLI.</description></item></channel></rss>