<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Syslog on davidstamen</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/tags/syslog/</link><description>Recent content in Syslog on davidstamen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2008–2018, Steve Francia and the Hugo Authors; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidstamen.com/tags/syslog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using PureStorage Powershell to Configure SysLog Servers</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2016/03/14/using-purestorage-powershell-to-configure-syslog-servers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2016/03/14/using-purestorage-powershell-to-configure-syslog-servers/</guid><description>Currently working on the final steps of getting our new equipment configured. The next step was to configure Syslog on all of our Pure Arrays. Another reason to script this task! Easily populate your arrays and server and at the click of a button you can configure all your arrays easily.
Pre-Requsites PureStorage Powershell SDK Link to Script Set-PureStorageSyslog.ps1 Preparing to Execute the Script The script is pretty straight forward, just need to define a few variables seen below and then you execute the script.</description></item><item><title>Using UCS PowerTool to Configure Syslog Servers</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2016/03/14/using-ucs-powertool-to-configure-syslog-servers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2016/03/14/using-ucs-powertool-to-configure-syslog-servers/</guid><description>Time for more UCS Scripting! This time to configure Syslog. The script is pretty straightforward, but nice to have to easily set up Syslog across multiple UCS domains.
Pre-Requsites UCS Powertool Link to Script Set-UcsSyslog.ps1 Preparing to Execute the Script The script is pretty straight forward, just need to define a few variables seen below and then you execute the script. I will walk you through the process.
1# UCS PowerTool Script that to set Syslog 2# @davidstamen 3# http://davidstamen.</description></item><item><title>Configuring ESXi 5.5 Syslog Collector</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2014/06/10/configuring-esxi-5-5-syslog-collector/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2014/06/10/configuring-esxi-5-5-syslog-collector/</guid><description>Thank you to everyone who listened to me on the EMEA vBrownbag. Here are copies of documentation and scripts on how to configure ESXi to use the Syslog collector.
Check the ESXi Syslog Collector Configuration Example: 1Foreach ($vmhost in (get-vmhost)){ 2$esxcli = Get-EsxCli -vmhost $vmhost 3$esxcli.system.syslog.config.get()} Setting the ESXi Syslog Collector Example: 1Foreach ($vmhost in (get-vmhost)){ 2$esxcli = Get-EsxCli -vmhost $vmhost 3$esxcli.system.syslog.config.set($null, $null, $null, $null,&amp;#34;udp://IPtoSyslogServer:514″) 4$esxcli.system.syslog.reload()} Post-Installation Changes If you wish to change the default port or maxsize of the syslog rotation, these can be changed by modifying the vmconfig-syslog.</description></item></channel></rss>