<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Azure on davidstamen</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/tags/azure/</link><description>Recent content in Azure on davidstamen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2008–2018, Steve Francia and the Hugo Authors; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 05:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidstamen.com/tags/azure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Navigating the Azure Cloud: Key Considerations for Strengthening Infrastructure Security with Azure Locks</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2023/08/28/navigating-the-azure-cloud-key-considerations-for-strengthening-infrastructure-security-with-azure-locks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2023/08/28/navigating-the-azure-cloud-key-considerations-for-strengthening-infrastructure-security-with-azure-locks/</guid><description>&lt;p>In today&amp;rsquo;s world, making sure your cloud infrastructure is secured is important. As you migrate to the cloud, the need to protect sensitive data, prevent accidental changes, and maintain compliance becomes increasingly crucial. One powerful tool in your arsenal to achieve this is Azure Locks. In this blog post, we will explore what Azure Locks are, why they are important, and how you can effectively utilize them to enhance the security of your Azure resources.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Power of PowerShell: Calculating Azure VMware Solution (AVS) Costs</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2023/08/21/the-power-of-powershell-calculating-azure-vmware-solution-avs-costs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2023/08/21/the-power-of-powershell-calculating-azure-vmware-solution-avs-costs/</guid><description>&lt;p>Gone are the days of manual calculations and complex spreadsheets to estimate costs. With the capabilities of PowerShell and automation tools we have the ability to streamline the collection of data. Through this blog I will guide you through the steps of utilizing PowerShell to calculate Azure VMware Solution costs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Navigating the Azure Cloud: Key Considerations for Azure VMware Solution (AVS)</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2023/08/16/navigating-the-azure-cloud-key-considerations-for-azure-vmware-solution-avs/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2023/08/16/navigating-the-azure-cloud-key-considerations-for-azure-vmware-solution-avs/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Azure VMware Solution (AVS) is a cloud service provided by Microsoft that allows organizations to seamlessly extend their on-premises VMware environments to the Microsoft Azure cloud. It essentially enables you to run and manage your existing VMware workloads in Azure without the need to rearchitect or refactor them.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Navigating the Azure Cloud: Key Considerations for Harnessing DNS with Azure Private Endpoints</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2023/08/15/navigating-the-azure-cloud-key-considerations-for-harnessing-dns-with-azure-private-endpoints/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2023/08/15/navigating-the-azure-cloud-key-considerations-for-harnessing-dns-with-azure-private-endpoints/</guid><description>&lt;p>One powerful tool that Azure offers to enhance security and privacy is the Azure Private Endpoint DNS. This innovative feature allows organizations to establish a private and secure connection to their Azure services, minimizing exposure to potential threats and breaches. This blog will highlight some considerations to be aware of when utilizing it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using Bicep to Deploy a Microsoft SQL on Azure VM with Cloud Block Store Volumes</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2023/05/17/using-bicep-to-deploy-a-microsoft-sql-on-azure-vm-with-cloud-block-store-volumes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2023/05/17/using-bicep-to-deploy-a-microsoft-sql-on-azure-vm-with-cloud-block-store-volumes/</guid><description>&lt;p>This blog will showcase how to deploy an Azure VM that has a configured Microsoft SQL Instance that is connected to a Cloud Block Store (CBS) volume. I have previously showcased VM &amp;amp; CBS deployments with both Powershell and Terraform, but its time to bring it to a new language!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using Bicep to Deploy an Azure Virtual Machine</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2023/05/15/using-bicep-to-deploy-an-azure-virtual-machine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2023/05/15/using-bicep-to-deploy-an-azure-virtual-machine/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to another blog on Automation! This one will be focused on deploying resources in Azure using Bicep. Follow along to understand what Bicep is and my thoughts on it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Understanding Block Storage in Microsoft Azure</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2022/04/29/understanding-block-storage-in-microsoft-azure/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2022/04/29/understanding-block-storage-in-microsoft-azure/</guid><description>&lt;p>When running workloads in the Public Cloud such as Microsoft Azure, you have a bunch of options when it comes to block storage. How do you know which one to pick? There are alot of choices&amp;ndash;tradeoffs, features and sprawl can also occur. In this blog I will cover the different types of disks available to help educate you on some of the purposes and limitations of each.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pure Cloud Block Store on Azure - Quick Launch</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2021/07/21/pure-cloud-block-store-on-azure-quick-launch/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2021/07/21/pure-cloud-block-store-on-azure-quick-launch/</guid><description>&lt;p>In previous posts I have covered use cases on how to utilize Pure Cloud Block Store (CBS), but if we look back I haven&amp;rsquo;t explained how it can be deployed. This blog will cover how to quickly launch the pre-requisites and get your Pure Cloud Block Store deployed in Azure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using the Pure Storage Cloud Block Store Terraform Provider for Azure</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2021/03/09/using-the-pure-storage-cloud-block-store-terraform-provider-for-azure/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2021/03/09/using-the-pure-storage-cloud-block-store-terraform-provider-for-azure/</guid><description>&lt;p>Im excited to announce the second release of the Pure Storage Cloud Block Store (CBS) Terraform Provider. This release includes support for Cloud Block Store on Azure! Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in and take a look.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cloud Block Store Use Cases for Microsoft Azure - Terraform Edition</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/azure-cbs-terraform-usecases/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/azure-cbs-terraform-usecases/</guid><description>&lt;p>Previously I explained how to use Terraform to Deploy an Azure VM. Now that Cloud Block Store iS GA in Azure, I can cover how to use Automation for Test/Dev, Disaster Recovery and Migration use cases to move workloads from on-premises to Microsoft Azure!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deploying a Windows Azure VM with Hashicorp Terraform to Microsoft Azure</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-avm-using-terraform/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/deploy-avm-using-terraform/</guid><description>&lt;p>As a followup to my previous post on Automating EC2 deployments, I figured why not show how this can also be done with Microsoft Azure? Check out how to launch an Azure VM instance and run some scripts to customize your installation.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>