<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Restore on davidstamen</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/tags/restore/</link><description>Recent content in Restore on davidstamen</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2008–2018, Steve Francia and the Hugo Authors; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidstamen.com/tags/restore/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Backup and Restore Kubernetes Applications Using Portworx</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/backup-restore-k8s-with-portworx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/backup-restore-k8s-with-portworx/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When deploying any enterprise application it is always important to think about the BC/DR strategy. Containers work really great from a Business Continuity perspective as they are stateless, but what happens if you lose the entire datacenter? What happens if you need to migrate an application to another site? PX-Backup from Portworx by Pure Storage is a great tool for this! Lets take a look how we can backup and restore applications using PX-Backup&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Considerations for vSphere Component Backup and Restore: Part 2</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2019/10/23/considerations-for-vsphere-component-backup-and-restore-part-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2019/10/23/considerations-for-vsphere-component-backup-and-restore-part-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Now that we have covered the considerations to backup each component in your vSphere Environment, it&amp;rsquo;s time to think about the rollback or restore process. In the previous post we discussed how to backup each individual component, in this post we will continue the conversation and discuss considerations to restore or rollback your vSphere Environment components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="platform-services-controller--vcenter-server"&gt;Platform Services Controller / vCenter Server&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When things don&amp;rsquo;t go right with an update, upgrade or configuration change of your Platform Services Controller or vCenter Server you need to understand the proper steps it takes to rollback. In these scenarios sometimes there may have been a failure in the process, or after a successful upgrade was completed, an incompatibility was found which would result in a rollback. A reason we see the need to rollback a vCenter Server is when a supporting solution such as a backup vendor or monitoring vendor is not compatible. In this case you will need to revert to the previous version.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Considerations for vSphere Component Backup and Restore: Part 1</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2019/10/21/considerations-for-vsphere-component-backup-and-restore-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2019/10/21/considerations-for-vsphere-component-backup-and-restore-part-1/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;You spend time planning and implementing updates, upgrades and configuration changes to vSphere Environments. Rollback or recovery is usually the last thing on the mind. Did you know there are multiple ways to successfully backup each component in a vSphere Environment? There are also many ways to recover those same components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this series we will talk about considerations to backup and restore or rollback your vSphere environment if we have a need to.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>