<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Automating your Pure Storage Infrastructure on davidstamen</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/series/automating-your-pure-storage-infrastructure/</link><description>Recent content in Automating your Pure Storage Infrastructure on davidstamen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2008–2018, Steve Francia and the Hugo Authors; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 08:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidstamen.com/series/automating-your-pure-storage-infrastructure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using PowerCLI to Provision your Pure Storage Infrastructure</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/08/17/using-powercli-to-provision-your-pure-storage-infrastructure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/08/17/using-powercli-to-provision-your-pure-storage-infrastructure/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the continuation of my Automating your Pure Storage Infrastructure blog series, next I will be covering how to use PowerCLI to provision your Pure Storage Infrastructure. This has been one of the most popular ways to automate provisioning, and alot of work has been put into making this an ideal automation solution.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using Python to Provision your Pure Storage Infrastructure</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/08/13/using-python-to-provision-your-pure-storage-infrastructure/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/08/13/using-python-to-provision-your-pure-storage-infrastructure/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the continuation of my Automating your Pure Storage Infrastructure blog series, next I will be covering how to use Python to provision your Pure Storage Infrastructure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using Ansible to Provision your Pure Storage Infrastructure</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/08/12/using-ansible-to-provision-your-pure-storage-infrastructure/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/08/12/using-ansible-to-provision-your-pure-storage-infrastructure/</guid><description>&lt;p>I mentioned previously that there are many things I love about the Pure Storage Flasharray, but one of my favorite is how easy it is to integrate into different automation solutions. In this blog I will cover how to use Ansible to provision your Pure Storage Infrastructure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using Terraform to Provision your Pure Storage Infrastructure</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/08/06/using-terraform-to-provision-your-pure-storage-infrastructure/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/08/06/using-terraform-to-provision-your-pure-storage-infrastructure/</guid><description>&lt;p>There are many things I love about the Pure Storage Flasharray, but one of my favorite is how easy it is to integrate into different automation solutions. In this blog I will cover how to use Terraform to provision your Pure Storage Infrastructure. This will be the first post of many that show how easy it is to accomplish the same task using multiple automation methods.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>