<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VSphere 6.5 on davidstamen</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/tags/vsphere-6.5/</link><description>Recent content in VSphere 6.5 on davidstamen</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2008–2018, Steve Francia and the Hugo Authors; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidstamen.com/tags/vsphere-6.5/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Unable to Update to vCenter Server 6.5 U2d on VCSA</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2018/11/19/unable-to-update-to-vcenter-server-6.5-u2d-on-vcsa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2018/11/19/unable-to-update-to-vcenter-server-6.5-u2d-on-vcsa/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When trying to update your vSphere 6.5 environment to vSphere 6.5u2d it may show that there are no available updates.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Upgrading Platform Services Controller and vCenter Server via the CLI Installer</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2018/10/05/upgrading-platform-services-controller-and-vcenter-server-via-the-cli-installer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 09:08:15 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2018/10/05/upgrading-platform-services-controller-and-vcenter-server-via-the-cli-installer/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The first topic we will cover in our Automating your vSphere Upgrade series is updating our core infrastructure. Upgrading Platform Services Controller(PSC)  and vCenter Server via the CLI installer. In our workshops one of the common things I hear is that most folks aren&amp;rsquo;t using the CLI based tools that have been included in the installer. I am a huge fan of these as they make migrations and upgrades seamless&amp;ndash;especially when having to perform the task if you have multiple PSC&amp;rsquo;s and vCenter Servers. Using the CLI tools don’t have to be intimidating, as we go through this blog we will cover some how-to&amp;rsquo;s and benefits of using the CLI based approach.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vCenter 6.5U1 Update Issues with VCHA Advanced Deployment</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2017/08/02/vcenter-6.5u1-update-issues-with-vcha-advanced-deployment/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 16:08:43 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2017/08/02/vcenter-6.5u1-update-issues-with-vcha-advanced-deployment/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;vSphere 6.5U1 was released on July 27th. This is an incremental update a lot of people wait for before upgrading from a previous version. I have been lucky to have been running on vSphere 6.5 for quite some time and have been enjoying it very much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously we never upgrade production first, if we can help it. I decided to attempt an upgrade on one of our QA vCenters that was deployed using the VCHA Advanced workflow. I followed my standard upgrade steps &lt;a href="https://davidstamen.com/vmware/vsphere-65-updating-appliance-configured-with-vcenter-ha/"&gt;Updating a VCHA 6.5 vCenter&lt;/a&gt; however when I went to failover the Active node to the upgraded passive/witness nodes, services would not start, I then noticed that the hostnames had reset to localhost.localdom which is kind of a big issue as vCenter relies on the hostname being set.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vSphere 6.5 - Updating Appliance configured with vCenter HA</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2017/02/03/vsphere-65-updating-appliance-configured-with-vcenter-ha/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2017/02/03/vsphere-65-updating-appliance-configured-with-vcenter-ha/</guid><description>&lt;h5 id="warning"&gt;Warning:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id="a-few-others-and-myself-have-noticed-that-when-updating-a-vcha-cluster-to-65u1-it-resets-the-hostname-to-localhostlocaldomain-stopping-vcenter-web-client-from-loading"&gt;A few others and myself have noticed that when updating a VCHA Cluster to 6.5U1 it resets the hostname to localhost.localdomain stopping vCenter Web Client from Loading.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id="it-seems-to-be-isolated-to-advanced-deployments-and-not-basic-i-would-recommend-destroying-your-vcha-cluster-updating-then-redeploying-in-this-scenario"&gt;&lt;del&gt;It seems to be isolated to Advanced Deployments and not Basic. I would recommend destroying your VCHA Cluster, updating, then redeploying in this scenario.&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id="warning2"&gt;Warning2:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id="it-also-seems-that-if-you-try-to-redeploy-vcha-advanced-after-an-upgrade-it-still-resets-the-hostname-i-have-a-case-opened-and-will-update-here-as-neccessary"&gt;It also seems that if you try to redeploy VCHA Advanced after an upgrade, it still resets the hostname, I have a case opened and will update here as neccessary.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first vSphere 6.5 Patch (6.5a) was just released! So far it seems there are a few critical fixes but the biggest feature is NSX 6.3 support.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vSphere 6.5 - vCenter HA Health Degraded due to Password Expiration</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2017/02/01/vcenter-ha-health-degraded-due-to-password-expiration/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2017/02/01/vcenter-ha-health-degraded-due-to-password-expiration/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite new features of vSphere 6.5 is definately vCenter HA. I was checking out alerts when I noticed i had an alarm for vCenter HA being degraded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://davidstamen.com/images/vchaerror1.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking through the GUI, I was unable to find anything in regards to why the Health was a warning and why the components would not sync. Then I remembered a previous case I had opened for VCHA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a log file located in &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;/var/log/vmware/vcha&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vSphere 6.5 - New License Import from My VMware</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2016/11/16/vsphere-65-new-license-import-from-myvmware/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2016/11/16/vsphere-65-new-license-import-from-myvmware/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;So as everyone has probably seen, &lt;a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/vsphere/2016/11/vmware-announces-general-availability-vsphere-6-5.html"&gt;vSphere 6.5&lt;/a&gt; is now GA. As usual right away I have upgraded the homelab and have already found a neat new feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you are adding in your VMware licenses, you now have an option to &lt;strong&gt;Import License Keys Data&amp;hellip;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To start you need to generate a report from &lt;a href="http://my.vmware.com"&gt;my.vmware.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Log in and Navigate to &lt;strong&gt;Download Reports&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Available Reports&lt;/strong&gt; dropdown, and select the &lt;strong&gt;Product Licenses, Details and History.&lt;/strong&gt; You will be asked which account you would like to select, and if there was a specific timeframe to select. In my case i have selected all accounts and then click Create.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>