<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Microsoft on davidstamen</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/categories/microsoft/</link><description>Recent content in Microsoft on davidstamen</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2008–2018, Steve Francia and the Hugo Authors; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidstamen.com/categories/microsoft/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Build and Publish a Powershell Module to the Powershell Gallery</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2022/09/01/build-and-publish-a-powershell-module-to-the-powershell-gallery/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2022/09/01/build-and-publish-a-powershell-module-to-the-powershell-gallery/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this blog we will dive into what is a Powershell Module, how its changed and then what can we do to build and publish the module to the Powershell Gallery. I recently did this presentation again at VMworld Explore 2022 and it was a hit, so I figured its finally time to get it here on the blog so it can be referenced and viewed year round.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using Powershell to Create Windows SMB Shares</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2016/08/09/using-powershell-to-create-windows-smb-shares/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2016/08/09/using-powershell-to-create-windows-smb-shares/</guid><description>I have been knee deep in migrations, so after clicking through a few times to create clustered file shares, I finally decided to script them. Here is that script I thought I would share. Thanksfully there was the NTFSSecurity module published by microsoft that makes permissions a breeze. You can get more details by viewing the module page.
Pre-Requsites NTFS Security Module Link to Script Create-SMBShare.ps1 Preparing to Execute the Script Fill in the appropriate variables, and execute the script.</description></item><item><title>Using Ansible to Run Powershell Scripts</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2016/02/04/using-ansible-to-run-powershell-scripts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2016/02/04/using-ansible-to-run-powershell-scripts/</guid><description>In the midst of playing with Ansible and figured my most common use case would be executing powershell scripts on remote servers, so scavenged around and put this together.
Pre-Requsites ansible ansible-winrm Link to Git Project ansible_powershell Preparing to Execute the Script This script assumes you have already installed and configured Ansible, downloaded the Git Repo and installed the WinRM python module.
Define your group variables. Create a hostgroup.yml file in this folder.</description></item><item><title>Using Vagrant to Deploy a 2012R2 DHCP Failover Cluster</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2015/10/01/using-vagrant-to-deploy-a-2012r2-dhcp-failover-cluster/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2015/10/01/using-vagrant-to-deploy-a-2012r2-dhcp-failover-cluster/</guid><description>So I am in the process of rolling out a new 2012R2 DHCP Server Cluster, and I thought i would share my scripts with the community.
I have also rolled it into a Vagrant package so you can easily test it on your own, and execute the scripts by themselves against your environment to deploy.
Here is a link to the GitHub repository containing all the code.
The code is also fairly simple, it pulls in data from a few .</description></item><item><title>Identify DirSync Distribution Groups in Office365</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2014/11/19/identity-dirsync-distribution-groups-in-office365/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2014/11/19/identity-dirsync-distribution-groups-in-office365/</guid><description>So after recently implementing directory sync i wanted to make sure any new groups were properly set up in active directory.
Unfortunately i was unable to find any commands so thanks to MS Support I was able to find a way to identify these. You would think it would be under Get-DistributionGroup but it is actually under Get-MSolGroup. After connecting via remote powershell you can run the below command to see all that are not synced.</description></item><item><title>Horizon View 6 - Single Sign On with Published Applications</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2014/10/29/horizon-view-6-single-sign-on-with-published-applications/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2014/10/29/horizon-view-6-single-sign-on-with-published-applications/</guid><description>So I have been working in a few situations where i have wanted to use Horizon 6 published (RDS) applications but having to either launch the Horizon View client within a VDI or have users be forced to logon again has been a deal breaker.
Upon further research i finally found the right combination of settings to allow users to launch the RDS Hosted Applications via a Shortcut and automatically login to the view client making this process seamless.</description></item><item><title>Office 365/Exchange EAC Pop Ups not working with Chrome 37</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2014/10/16/office-365exchange-eac-pop-ups-not-working-with-chrome-37/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2014/10/16/office-365exchange-eac-pop-ups-not-working-with-chrome-37/</guid><description>Chrome depreciated one of the features that allowed these popups to work, here is a temporary workaround to get it working.
Download the Chrome Policy Plugin here
Open the zip file you just downloaded and locate the .ADM file that best matches your system: Extract the .ADM file to any folder on your hard drive Go to Start &amp;gt; Run, and run gpedit.msc Right-click Local Computer Policy &amp;gt; Computer Configuration &amp;gt; Administrative Templates, and select Add/Remove Templates: Add the adm template that you saved to disk earlier: You should now see the template underneath a Google &amp;gt; Google Chrome section within Administrative Templates Depending on which operating system you have, it might be under a Classic Administrative Templates (ADM) folder: Click on Google Chrome in the left-hand pane and then double-click on the item called Enable deprecated web platform features in the list within the right-hand pane: NOTE: It helps to sort the table in the right-hand pane by the Setting column in order to find the Enable deprecated web platform features item more easily.</description></item><item><title>Unable to Install .NET 3.5 on Server 2012R2</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2014/09/11/unable-to-install-net-3-5-on-server-2012r2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2014/09/11/unable-to-install-net-3-5-on-server-2012r2/</guid><description>So upon trying to install .Net 3.5 on a new server today it would not allow me to, it kept telling me the source files were unavailable even after pointing to source directly to multiple ISO&amp;rsquo;s and copied the files locally.
Upon further research I stumbled across this microsoft KB article and used it to ultimately find my fix. KB2734782
Here are the full steps I followed to get .NET installed.</description></item><item><title>Blocking Attachments With Executable Content</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2014/05/01/blocking-attachments-with-executable-content/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2014/05/01/blocking-attachments-with-executable-content/</guid><description>I don&amp;rsquo;t know whats going on in the past few weeks but the sheer amount of zeroday exploits via email have risen. To protect yourselves against this I would recommend setting up a transport rule to drop or reject any email with executable content. This can be done for Exchange 2013 or Office365 (Exchange Online).
Login to Exchange Admin Center using administrative credentials On the left pane select &amp;ldquo;Mail flow&amp;rdquo; On the top pane select &amp;quot; Rules&amp;quot; Click on the &amp;ldquo;+&amp;rdquo; sign and select create a new rule Give a name to the rule and select &amp;ldquo;more options&amp;rdquo; at the bottom of the page.</description></item></channel></rss>