<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VCenter HA on davidstamen.com</title>
    <link>/tags/vcenter-ha/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VCenter HA on davidstamen.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 16:08:43 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/vcenter-ha/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>vCenter 6.5U1 Update Issues with VCHA Advanced Deployment</title>
      <link>/2017/08/02/vcenter-6.5u1-update-issues-with-vcha-advanced-deployment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 16:08:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/08/02/vcenter-6.5u1-update-issues-with-vcha-advanced-deployment/</guid>
      <description>vSphere 6.5U1 was released on July 27th. This is an incremental update a lot of people wait for before upgrading from a previous version. I have been lucky to have been running on vSphere 6.5 for quite some time and have been enjoying it very much.
Obviously we never upgrade production first, if we can help it. I decided to attempt an upgrade on one of our QA vCenters that was deployed using the VCHA Advanced workflow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vSphere 6.5 - Updating Appliance configured with vCenter HA</title>
      <link>/2017/02/03/vsphere-65-updating-appliance-configured-with-vcenter-ha/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/02/03/vsphere-65-updating-appliance-configured-with-vcenter-ha/</guid>
      <description>Warning: A few others and myself have noticed that when updating a VCHA Cluster to 6.5U1 it resets the hostname to localhost.localdomain stopping vCenter Web Client from Loading. It seems to be isolated to Advanced Deployments and not Basic. I would recommend destroying your VCHA Cluster, updating, then redeploying in this scenario. Warning2: It also seems that if you try to redeploy VCHA Advanced after an upgrade, it still resets the hostname, I have a case opened and will update here as neccessary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vSphere 6.5 - vCenter HA Health Degraded due to Password Expiration</title>
      <link>/2017/02/01/vcenter-ha-health-degraded-due-to-password-expiration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/02/01/vcenter-ha-health-degraded-due-to-password-expiration/</guid>
      <description>One of my favorite new features of vSphere 6.5 is definately vCenter HA. I was checking out alerts when I noticed i had an alarm for vCenter HA being degraded.
Looking through the GUI, I was unable to find anything in regards to why the Health was a warning and why the components would not sync. Then I remembered a previous case I had opened for VCHA.
There is a log file located in /var/log/vmware/vcha</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vSphere 6.5 - vCenter HA (VCHA) Issues</title>
      <link>/2016/11/21/vsphere-65-vcha-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/11/21/vsphere-65-vcha-issues/</guid>
      <description>So as everyone has probably seen, vSphere 6.5 is now GA. One of the features i have been waiting for the most is vCenter HA. I have spent some time trying to get this working in my lab. Unfortunately after countless tries i was stuck. Thanks to folks in the vExpert Slack for helping me try to resolve this, but unfortunately this was a case for VMware Support.
Every time I would try to configure vCenter HA using the Advanced Wizard, I would get the following error.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>