<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vmware on davidstamen.com</title>
    <link>http://davidstamen.com/tags/vmware/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vmware on davidstamen.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://davidstamen.com/tags/vmware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>vExpert 2017</title>
      <link>http://davidstamen.com/2017/02/08/vexpert-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidstamen.com/2017/02/08/vexpert-2017/</guid>
      <description>I am honored to have been selected as a VMware vExpert once again for 2017!
This is my fifth year as a vExpert (2013,2014,2015,2016 and 2017). It has been great to see the community grow and the amount of vExperts increase. I did a quick count, and in 2016 we are up to 1464 vExperts!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vSphere 6.5 - Updating Appliance configured with vCenter HA</title>
      <link>http://davidstamen.com/2017/02/03/vsphere-65-updating-appliance-configured-with-vcenter-ha/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidstamen.com/2017/02/03/vsphere-65-updating-appliance-configured-with-vcenter-ha/</guid>
      <description>Warning: A few others and myself have noticed that when updating a VCHA Cluster to 6.5U1 it resets the hostname to localhost.localdomain stopping vCenter Web Client from Loading. It seems to be isolated to Advanced Deployments and not Basic. I would recommend destroying your VCHA Cluster, Udating, then Redeploying in this scenario.** The first vSphere 6.5 Patch (6.5a) was just released! So far it seems there are a few critical fixes but the biggest feature is NSX 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vSphere 6.5 - vCenter HA Health Degraded due to Password Expiration</title>
      <link>http://davidstamen.com/2017/02/01/vcenter-ha-health-degraded-due-to-password-expiration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidstamen.com/2017/02/01/vcenter-ha-health-degraded-due-to-password-expiration/</guid>
      <description>One of my favorite new features of vSphere 6.5 is definately vCenter HA. I was checking out alerts when I noticed i had an alarm for vCenter HA being degraded.
Looking through the GUI, I was unable to find anything in regards to why the Health was a warning and why the components would not sync. Then I remembered a previous case I had opened for VCHA.
There is a log file located in /var/log/vmware/vcha</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional Branding of vSphere Web Client Logon Page</title>
      <link>http://davidstamen.com/2017/01/19/functional-branding-of-vsphere-web-client-logon-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidstamen.com/2017/01/19/functional-branding-of-vsphere-web-client-logon-page/</guid>
      <description>I had a use case I wanted to investigate in regards to the new VCHA that is part of VMware vCenter Server 6.5. One thing I noticed, is when you have VCHA configured, there is no way to know which node of the HA cluster you are connecting to without being logged on.
As people have noted before William Lam&amp;rsquo;s - How to Customize Webclient Login UI
I figured since I am using the embedded SSO, I could update the login page to show any information for that particular node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the VMware Content Libray Assistant Fling</title>
      <link>http://davidstamen.com/2016/12/29/using-the-vmware-content-libray-assistant-fling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidstamen.com/2016/12/29/using-the-vmware-content-libray-assistant-fling/</guid>
      <description>So VMware Flings have been on a roll recently. They have released what they call &amp;ldquo;VMware Content Library Assistant.&amp;rdquo; This is a java based CLI app, that connects to your vCenter and searchers for your templates and then automatically creates and uploads them.
You can find the fling at the following URL&amp;hellip;https://labs.vmware.com/flings/vsphere-content-library-assistant)
Once you download the fling, you can just run the following command.
java -jar sphere-content-library-assistant-1.0.jar -s servername -u username -p password  In my case my java home isn&amp;rsquo;t setup on my mac so I had to run the following command to get it to work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vSphere 6.5 - vCenter HA (VCHA) Issues</title>
      <link>http://davidstamen.com/2016/11/21/vsphere-65-vcha-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidstamen.com/2016/11/21/vsphere-65-vcha-issues/</guid>
      <description>So as everyone has probably seen, vSphere 6.5 is now GA. One of the features i have been waiting for the most is vCenter HA. I have spent some time trying to get this working in my lab. Unfortunately after countless tries i was stuck. Thanks to folks in the vExpert Slack for helping me try to resolve this, but unfortunately this was a case for VMware Support.
Every time I would try to configure vCenter HA using the Advanced Wizard, I would get the following error.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vSphere 6.5 - New License Import from My VMware</title>
      <link>http://davidstamen.com/2016/11/16/vsphere-65-new-license-import-from-myvmware/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidstamen.com/2016/11/16/vsphere-65-new-license-import-from-myvmware/</guid>
      <description>So as everyone has probably seen, vSphere 6.5 is now GA. As usual right away I have upgraded the homelab and have already found a neat new feature.
When you are adding in your VMware licenses, you now have an option to Import License Keys Data&amp;hellip;
To start you need to generate a report from my.vmware.com.
 Log in and Navigate to Download Reports
 Click on the Available Reports dropdown, and select the Product Licenses, Details and History.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting Cisco ENIC and FNIC Drivers with VMware Update Manager 6.x</title>
      <link>http://davidstamen.com/2016/04/08/troubleshooting-cisco-enic-and-fnic-drivers-with-vmware-update-manager-6x/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidstamen.com/2016/04/08/troubleshooting-cisco-enic-and-fnic-drivers-with-vmware-update-manager-6x/</guid>
      <description>I have been having issues ever since I updated to vSphere 6.x getting the Cisco Drivers to properly update through VMware Update Manager(VUM). Every time I would run through a compliance check, they would always report they were up to date even when they were running an older version.
I have recently made a breakthrough working with VMware Support and stumbling through some old blogs. Cisco Support has been terrible on this issue and after repeated attempts to get this case escalated i think the 10th time is a charm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vExpert 2016</title>
      <link>http://davidstamen.com/2016/02/05/vexpert-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidstamen.com/2016/02/05/vexpert-2016/</guid>
      <description>I am honored to have been selected as a VMware vExpert once again for 2016!
This is my fourth year as a vExpert (2013,2014,2015 and 2016). It has been great to see the community grow and the amount of vExperts increase. I did a quick count, and in 2016 we are up to 1360 vExperts!
Can&amp;rsquo;t wait to see what this year brings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unable to Boot EFI VM on ESXi FC Storage</title>
      <link>http://davidstamen.com/2016/01/13/unable-to-boot-efi-vm-on-esxi-fc-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidstamen.com/2016/01/13/unable-to-boot-efi-vm-on-esxi-fc-storage/</guid>
      <description>For the past week, I have been troubleshooting the strangest issue. I have been attempting to move some Windows 8.1 VM&amp;rsquo;s from our legacy datacenter(iSCSI) to our new datacenter(FC).
Whenever I would move the VM to our new DC, it would fail to boot properly. It would boot straight to Windows Recovery. If I moved the same VM to any other type of storage(NFS, iSCSI, Local) the VM would boot perfectly fine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading VCSA from 6.0 U1a to 6.0U1b using CLI</title>
      <link>http://davidstamen.com/2016/01/12/upgrading-vcsa-from-60-u1a-to-60u1b/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidstamen.com/2016/01/12/upgrading-vcsa-from-60-u1a-to-60u1b/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my post about upgrading your VMware vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) to 6.0 U1b.
This process is very straight forward. We will begin with updating our Platform Service Controllers (PSC) and then proceed with the vCenter Appliance.
 SSH to your Primary PSC. If you are currently in the bash shell, type appliancesh to switch shells to run the update. Run software-packages install &amp;ndash;url &amp;ndash;acceptEulas to download and install the packages from the VMware Repo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using CLI to Manage DVS Host Uplinks</title>
      <link>http://davidstamen.com/2015/11/30/using-cli-to-manage-dvs-host-uplinks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidstamen.com/2015/11/30/using-cli-to-manage-dvs-host-uplinks/</guid>
      <description>Ever needed to modify a DVS uplink configuration from ESXi Shell? I am currently troubleshooting some issues with DVS uplinks no longer being assigned on reboot.
As a heads up. If you are doing this on ESXi 6.0.. don&amp;rsquo;t. It can cause an issue with the proxy DVS having different ID than the actual DVS causing my original issue, still working with VMware Support to find out more details.
After &amp;ldquo;Restoring Network Configuration&amp;rdquo; a few too many times, I finally realized I could just add the uplinks back via CLI until support can figure out why this is occurring, here are the details on how to manage the uplinks on a DVS via CLI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disconnected vNIC&#39;s?</title>
      <link>http://davidstamen.com/2015/11/18/disconnected-vnics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidstamen.com/2015/11/18/disconnected-vnics/</guid>
      <description>Ever wonder why a VM isn&amp;rsquo;t on the network?
I was working on deploying some test VM&amp;rsquo;s and for some reason all the VM&amp;rsquo;s that were cloned decided to start with the network disconnected, and the connect on power on was also not selected.
I decided to throw together this quick one-liner that will make sure every VM is set to start connected on power on and is currently connected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unregistering vSphere 6 VCSA from PSC</title>
      <link>http://davidstamen.com/2015/10/13/unregistering-vsphere-6-vcsa-from-psc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidstamen.com/2015/10/13/unregistering-vsphere-6-vcsa-from-psc/</guid>
      <description>So I am in the process of doing some vSphere 6 testing and needed to test a redeployment of one of my VCSA&amp;rsquo;s. The problem is when I went to redeploy it I got the following error.
Decoding the error, I pretty much figured that the object already existed in the SSO database and I needed to delete the existing object. Here is how you do that.
 Log in as root to the appliance shell of the Platform Services Controller appliance with which the vCenter Server Appliance is registered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ESXi 5.5 Update 3a Released</title>
      <link>http://davidstamen.com/2015/10/06/esxi-55-update-3a-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidstamen.com/2015/10/06/esxi-55-update-3a-released/</guid>
      <description>ESXi 5.5 Update 3a and its associated patch have been released. If you have been following KB2133118 in regards to the the Snapshot Consolidation causing Virtual Machines to crash a fix is now available.
If you are currently running ESXi 5.5 U3 you can use update manager to install the patch.
If you are looking to install ESXi 5.5 U3 from scratch or update from a previous version you should make sure you update to 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ESXi 6.0 Update 1a Released</title>
      <link>http://davidstamen.com/2015/10/06/esxi-60-update-1a-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidstamen.com/2015/10/06/esxi-60-update-1a-released/</guid>
      <description>ESXi 6.0 Update 1a has been released. If you have been following KB2124669 in regards to the the NETDEV WATCHDOG issue causing an ESXi host to hang. The update is now available.
If you are currently running ESXi 6.0/6.0U1 you can use update manager to install the update.
If you are looking to install ESXi 6.0 U1 from scratch or update from a previous version you should make sure you update to use the latest ISO.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unable to SSH to vSphere 6 VCSA or PSC</title>
      <link>http://davidstamen.com/2015/09/21/unable-to-ssh-to-vsphere-6-vcsa-or-psc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidstamen.com/2015/09/21/unable-to-ssh-to-vsphere-6-vcsa-or-psc/</guid>
      <description>So I am in the midst of setting up a vSphere 6 POC and it has been a bit since I played with it. I came across a problem I thought i would document and share.
While trying to setup my Platform Service Controllers for HA. I was having issues sshing into the appliance. I kept on getting errors, that the packet sizes were too big or just authentication would fail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unable to join PSC to Domain via Webclient</title>
      <link>http://davidstamen.com/2015/09/21/unable-to-join-psc-to-domain-via-webclient/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidstamen.com/2015/09/21/unable-to-join-psc-to-domain-via-webclient/</guid>
      <description>I am actually pretty surprised this bug still exists. I came across this issue with my first deployment of vSphere 6. Now I am circling back around to do a POC and it still exists.
When trying to join a Platform Services Controller to the domain via the vSphere Webclient I get the following error: &amp;ldquo;java.lang.reflect.invocationTargetException&amp;rdquo;
There are currently two workarounds now with 6.0U1 I am aware of.
 The first method is to join to the domain using the CLI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vSphere 6.0 Update 1 Released</title>
      <link>http://davidstamen.com/2015/09/10/vsphere-60-update-1-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidstamen.com/2015/09/10/vsphere-60-update-1-released/</guid>
      <description>Today vSphere 6.0 U1 is released. This is normally the update everyone waits for before upgrading their production environments to the latest version. I think the first time in awhile, a lot of people will wait.
You see, VMware has had a bug KB2124669 since ESXi 6.0 that can cause an ESXi host to randomly lose connection, freeze and overall act really terrible. With the release of 6.0U1 it still exists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vSphere6 - Unable to use session credentials</title>
      <link>http://davidstamen.com/2015/04/13/vsphere6-unable-to-use-session-credentials/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidstamen.com/2015/04/13/vsphere6-unable-to-use-session-credentials/</guid>
      <description>So one thing I have come across with a few VCSA6 installs was the inability to use login with current credentials via the Web client or vSphere client.
Working with VMware support we were finally able to get it working with a few tweaks and there is a current pending KB that has not been published yet. (KB2113038) I have been told this affects both an embedded deployment (VCSA and PSC together) and external deployment (VCSA and PSC seperate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vSphere 5.x Storage vMotion Does Not Rename Virtual Machine Files.</title>
      <link>http://davidstamen.com/2014/05/21/vsphere-5-x-storage-vmotion-does-not-rename-virtual-machine-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidstamen.com/2014/05/21/vsphere-5-x-storage-vmotion-does-not-rename-virtual-machine-files/</guid>
      <description>After upgrading vCenter this functionality is no longer enabled by default. Please perform the following steps to enable rename of files upon successful Storage vMotion.
 Log into the vSphere Client as an Administrator Click Administration &amp;gt; vCenter Server Settings Click Advanced Settings Add this advanced parameter key: provisioning.relocate.enableRename Set the value to: true Click Add Click OK Restart the VMware VirtualCenter Server service for the changes to take effect  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HA Error: Datastore Heartbeat is less than 2</title>
      <link>http://davidstamen.com/2014/05/08/ha-error-datastore-heartbeat-is-less-than-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidstamen.com/2014/05/08/ha-error-datastore-heartbeat-is-less-than-2/</guid>
      <description>If you are configuring a cluster with less than 2 datastores, you will receive an HA warning &amp;ldquo;The number of heartbeat datastores for host is 1, which is less than required: 2&amp;rdquo; You can add an option to the HA Advanced Options to supress this warning.
 Log in to vCenter Server Right-click the cluster and click Edit Settings Click vSphere HA &amp;gt; Advanced Options Under Option, add an entry for das.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HA Error: Network Redundancy</title>
      <link>http://davidstamen.com/2014/05/08/ha-error-network-redundancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidstamen.com/2014/05/08/ha-error-network-redundancy/</guid>
      <description>When setting up a cluster for testing you may not have 2 nics to use for management. to bypass the warning you can configure HA to not alert you for this issue.
To perform the steps in the c# client.  From the VMware Infrastructure Client, right-click on the cluster and click Edit Settings. Select vSphere HA and click Advanced Options. In the Options column, enter das.ignoreRedundantNetWarning In the Value column, type true Click OK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enable SSH on vSphere Management Assistant 5.0</title>
      <link>http://davidstamen.com/2014/05/01/enable-ssh-on-vma-5-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidstamen.com/2014/05/01/enable-ssh-on-vma-5-0/</guid>
      <description>While continuing to build out my lab for VCAP-DCA today I had to deploy the vMA (vSphere Management Assistant). Upon deployment i tried to SSH to it and unfortunately was not able to. By default SSH is turned off, perform the steps below to enable it.
 Logon to vMA via a Console Session Run &amp;lsquo;sudo vi /etc/hosts.allow&amp;rsquo; Scroll to the very bottom and type i to insert content into the file.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>