<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>vRealize Orchestrator on davidstamen</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/tags/vrealize-orchestrator/</link><description>Recent content in vRealize Orchestrator on davidstamen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2008–2018, Steve Francia and the Hugo Authors; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidstamen.com/tags/vrealize-orchestrator/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using Pure1 Meta for Intelligent Datastore Selection and VM Provisioning</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/11/11/using-pure1-meta-for-intelligent-datastore-selection-and-vm-provisioning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/11/11/using-pure1-meta-for-intelligent-datastore-selection-and-vm-provisioning/</guid><description>&lt;p>When it comes to monitoring your Pure Storage environment Pure1 is a great place for that. It is also a great place to use your analytic&amp;rsquo;s data to your advantage and use it for intelligent VMware provisioning! In this blog post I will cover how to use this data to your advantage to make sure you can easily deploy VM&amp;rsquo;s to the most optimal array and datastore.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What's New in the Pure Storage vRealize Orchestrator Plugin 3.5</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/whats-new-purestorage-vro-35/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/whats-new-purestorage-vro-35/</guid><description>&lt;p>Released on July 30, 2020 the latest vRO plugin for vRealize 7.x is here!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Configuring vRealize Orchestrator to use Pure1 Integration</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/06/05/configuring-vrealize-orchestrator-to-use-pure1-integration/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/06/05/configuring-vrealize-orchestrator-to-use-pure1-integration/</guid><description>&lt;p>The more I play with our integrations the more I am impressed. My latest project within vRealize Orchestrator had me utilizing our Pure1 integration. This post will cover how to generate the needed pieces to configure the Pure1 Integration within vRO.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>vExpert Cloud Management 2020 Award</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/04/07/vexpert-cloud-management-2020-award/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/04/07/vexpert-cloud-management-2020-award/</guid><description>&lt;p>VMware and their vExpert Program has announced the vExpert Sub-Program announcements and I am glad to see I have been accepted into the vExpert Cloud Management group!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using vRealize Automation with the Pure Storage vRealize Orchestrator Plugin</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/03/20/using-vrealize-automation-with-the-pure-storage-vrealize-orchestrator-plugin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/03/20/using-vrealize-automation-with-the-pure-storage-vrealize-orchestrator-plugin/</guid><description>&lt;p>Moving forward with Automation, we will now expand our horizons past vRealize Orchestrator (vRO) into vRealize Automation (vRA)! Our integration with vRA utilizes the vRO Plugin and allows users to self-provision their infrastructure using all the goodness included with vRA such as blueprints, approval workflows and reservations. Lets Dive in and take a look!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using the Pure Storage vRealize Orchestrator Plugin</title><link>https://davidstamen.com/2020/03/16/using-the-pure-storage-vrealize-orchestrator-plugin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidstamen.com/2020/03/16/using-the-pure-storage-vrealize-orchestrator-plugin/</guid><description>&lt;p>Adding to the series of VMware and Pure Storage blogs is Automation! When it comes to automating your VMware Environment with Pure Storage we have a vRO Plugin for you! Dive in and take a look at how you can get your environment automated.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>